Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I don't know.
我不知道。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Hello everyone, hope you can hear me well.
大家好，希望您能听到我的声音。
I'm without a camera today, so let me know if it's still good.
我今天没有相机，所以让我知道它是否还不错。
Yeah, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
welcome to our fourth week of the epf study group and uh after uh covering the intro the execution
欢迎来到我们EPF研究小组的第四周，UH涵盖执行介绍后UH
the consensus layer um now we will dive into how all of this that we discussed actually gets tested
共识层，现在我们将深入研究我们讨论的所有这些实际测试
and secure um this is very important uh for many people the testing sounds uh like something
嗯，这对许多人来说非常重要，测试听起来像是什么
strange like why why should we care about it it's just like part of the development but it's
奇怪的是为什么我们为什么要关心它就像开发的一部分，但这是
it's actually one of the most important parts of the whole Ethereum,
它实际上是整个以太坊中最重要的部分之一，
I would say as important as the topics as we discussed before,
我会说的与我们之前讨论的主题一样重要，
because, well, this is what prevents the whole network from going belly up, as we say.
因为，正如我们所说，这是阻止整个网络腹部浮出水的原因。
And for this week's talks, we got the best possible person to discuss this topic,
在本周的会谈中，我们有最好的人讨论此主题，
and it's Mario Vega, our colleague from EF testing and security team,
这是我们来自EF测试和安全团队的同事Mario Vega，
who have been working on the testing since like autumn 2021, I believe,
我相信，像2021年秋天以来一直从事测试的人
a year before the merge.
合并前一年。
And during this first year, he, well, he overhauled a lot of the testing infrastructure,
在第一年，他对许多测试基础设施进行了大修，
which helped for the merge to actually happen.
这有助于合并实际发生。
And until today, he is one of the major forces behind all of the testing
直到今天，他还是所有测试背后的主要力量之一
of the upgrades and hard works and so on.
升级和努力工作等等。
So, yeah, I'm very, very happy to have Mario here today.
所以，是的，我今天很高兴今天在这里有Mario。
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Can you guys hear me?
你们能听到我的声音吗？
Yeah, all good.
是的，一切都很好。
Yeah, thank you so much for joining.
是的，非常感谢您加入。
You can share your slides here in the Harrison button.
您可以在Harrison按钮中共享幻灯片。
Give me just one second.
只给我一秒钟。
And yeah, for everybody listening, joining in now,
是的，对于每个人都在听，现在加入的人，
please use the week four in the study group Discord.
请在研究小组不和谐中使用第四周。
We just opened a thread for this week's presentation,
我们刚刚为本周的演讲打开了一个线程，
so you can ask questions there.
因此，您可以在那里提出问题。
Feel free to ask anything during the talk,
在谈话期间随时问任何事情，
and we will try to get it answered
我们将尝试将其回答
either within the thread,
要么在线程中，
or we will ask Mario directly.
否则我们将直接问马里奥。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
Yeah, and we got the slides. Awesome.
是的，我们得到了幻灯片。惊人的。
Does that work? Does it look okay?
那起作用吗？看起来还可以吗？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Okay, let me...
好吧，让我...
Yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
You just click on the slideshow if you're looking for that on the right.
如果您在右边寻找它，只需单击幻灯片。
Yeah.
是的。
The big button.
大按钮。
Right, there you go.
是的，你去了。
Yeah, that one. There you go.
是的，那个。你去。
Awesome. Thank you so much.
惊人的。太感谢了。
The stage is yours. Go ahead.
舞台是你的。前进。
Perfect. So yeah, thanks for the presentation. My name is Mario, Mario Vega. I'm from the
完美的。是的，感谢您的演讲。我叫马里奥·维加（Mario Vega）。我来自
EF. I work in the EF testing team. I focus mainly on developing the tests and the functional,
EF。我在EF测试团队中工作。我主要专注于开发测试和功能，
mainly the functional testing part of the entire testing setup that Ethereum uses to actually work
以太坊用来实际工作的整个测试设置的功能测试部分
properly. So I'm gonna dig in a little bit on what I do and a little bit of what some of our peers
适当地。所以我要挖掘自己的工作和一些同龄人的一点点
in the EF do, mainly testing security also, and also DevOps, a little bit of that.
在EF中，也主要是测试安全性，以及DevOps，其中一点点。
So yeah, let's get started.
是的，让我们开始。
So today's topics I'm going to be covering, how is the execution layer testing done?
因此，我将要介绍的今天的主题，执行层测试如何完成？
Mainly the EBM testing, which is a very important part of the consensus of the chain.
主要是EBM测试，这是链条共识的非常重要的部分。
We have two main repositories for this.
我们有两个主要存储库。
One is the Ethereum test, and the other one is,
一个是以太坊测试，另一个是
and the other one we just started working on
另一个我们刚刚开始工作的
it's called the Ethereum Execution Spec Tests.
它称为以太坊执行规格测试。
And we're gonna go a little bit of that.
我们会做一点。
And I'm also gonna do a little bit of a demo
我也会做一些演示
on how to run these tests, how they work
关于如何运行这些测试，它们如何工作
and their inner workings is gonna be really, really good.
他们的内在运作将非常非常好。
The, I'm gonna cover it out just a little bit
，我要掩盖一点
consensus layer testing, mainly the theorem consensus specs, which is the repo that
共识层测试，主要是定理共识规范，这是回购
basically does everything. It's one solution for the specification and the testing it's all covered
基本上做了一切。这是规格和测试的一种解决方案
inside of this repo. I'm gonna just go over it a little bit, not in the greatest detail, because
在此存储库中。我要仔细研究一下，而不是最细节，因为
this is not the main area that we work currently, I mean the EF team, the testing team.
这不是我们目前工作的主要领域，我的意思是EF团队，测试团队。
I'm going to be going over a little bit of a cross-layer interrupt testing, which is a very important part now that we have two layers, the execution layer and the consensus layer part.
我将仔细研究跨层中断测试，这是一个非常重要的部分，因为我们有两个层，执行层和共识层部分。
The team, the testing team, works mainly on Hive, but we also have the devnets, childworks, and testnet, which are the work of the DevOps team.
团队，测试团队主要在Hive上工作，但我们也有Devnets，Childworks和Testnet，这是DevOps团队的工作。
I'm gonna cover a little bit of that,
我要掩盖一点，
but we're going to go a little bit deeper on Hive,
但是我们将在Hive上更深入一点，
which is the one that I work with the most.
这是我最合作的。
And we are gonna do a little bit of a demo in that too,
而且我们也会在其中做一些演示
how to run tests, how they work,
如何运行测试，如何工作，
the inner workings and all that stuff.
内在的工作和所有这些东西。
And finally, a little bit of the security,
最后，一点点安全，
what the potential issues are,
潜在的问题是什么，
What are the rewards if you guys are into finding security issues?
如果你们要找到安全问题，有什么回报？
What can you earn if you disclose properly and you find any security-related issues?
如果您正确披露并发现任何与安全有关的问题，您可以赚钱？
That's going to be what we cover today.
那将是我们今天所涵盖的。
And also how to publicly disclose your deaths after any security incident has been addressed.
以及在解决任何安全事件后，如何公开披露您的死亡。
So, yeah, we're going to start with the EVM testing, which is, I wouldn't say the simplest.
所以，是的，我们将从EVM测试开始，这是我不会说最简单的。
It's very complex, but the setup is the most straightforward.
它非常复杂，但是设置最直接。
EVM testing, the main purpose is basically just to try to verify that every single Ethereum execution client adheres to this specification.
EVM测试，主要目的基本上只是试图验证每个以太坊执行客户端都遵守此规范。
This is extremely important because not adhering to the specification means a positive potential fork in the chain if there are no consensus on what was executed through all the transactions.
这是非常重要的，因为不遵守规范意味着如果对通过所有交易执行的内容尚无共识，则在链中具有正势。
it's the setup is super simple for for even testing basically you have the same input for
这是设置非常简单，对于即使测试基本上您都有相同的输入
every client and you must register that every single client gets the same exact output given
每个客户端，您必须注册每个客户都将获得与给定的确切输出相同的
the same environment pre-state and hard work activation rules which will be going over in a
相同的环境预期和艰苦的激活规则将在
little bit. So yeah, I wanted to cover just this important characteristics of a
一点。是的，我想涵盖这个重要的特征
test because these are like the most, the things that we focus on the most when
测试是因为这些是最多的，所以当我们最关注的事情
writing our tests for the ABM. And the first one is the pre-state. And I'll go
为ABM编写我们的测试。第一个是预状态。我去
back a little bit so just just explain a little bit uh of how it's discomposed so the blockchain
回来一点，所以只需解释一下它如何变形的一点，以便区块链
uh the ethereum blockchain contains uh the state um in general this is where everything lives
嗯，以太坊区块链包含uh状态，这是一切生活的地方
everything that that comprises the ethereum blockchain it's it lives on the state this
包括以太坊区块链的一切
contains the smart contracts the balances the nonce uh the code of the smart contracts
包含智能合约，余额nonce uh smart合同的代码
the and also most importantly the storage of the smart contract so every single smart contract
也是最重要的是智能合约的存储，因此每个智能合约
contains at least code and storage this is very important part because when you're writing your
至少包含代码和存储，这是非常重要的部分，因为当您编写您的
smart contract um you normally want to save some information uh that will uh be preserved
智能合约um，您通常想保存一些将保留的信息
even after so even after the first transaction where you launch your smart contract
即使在您启动智能合约的第一次交易之后，即使在此之后
on the next transactions you will want to access information from the previous ones.
在接下来的交易中，您将需要访问上一张交易。
So this is the storage, it's a very important part of the blockchain.
因此，这是存储空间，这是区块链的非常重要的部分。
And when we set up the EVM testing, this is the most pivotal part of the test,
当我们设置EVM测试时，这是测试中最关键的部分，
because we don't test the entire mainnet, for example, because it's huge.
例如，因为我们没有测试整个主网，因为它很大。
What you have right now in mainnet, you have contracts that have
您现在在Mainnet中拥有的，您有合同
an insane amount of storage, an insane amount of key values that they will use.
疯狂的存储空间，它们将使用的疯狂键值。
For example, Uniswap, they use a lot of storage to store every single user's,
例如，uniswap，他们使用大量存储存储每个用户的存储
for example, balances in each token, and so on and so forth.
例如，每个令牌中的平衡，等等。
But for the simplest testing, so normally when we write an EDM test,
但是对于最简单的测试，因此通常在我们编写EDM测试时，
We normally just want to focus on a small slice of what the EVM executes.
通常，我们只想专注于EVM执行的一小部分。
So for that, we generate the pre-state.
因此，我们生成了预状态。
The pre-state is something that we know for sure is going to be before we execute any of the transactions.
在执行任何交易之前，我们肯定会知道的是预期的。
And this is very important.
这很重要。
I will explain a little bit further in the following slides.
我将在以下幻灯片中进一步解释。
But that's it.
但就是这样。
yes and yeah the another important part of of this is the environment so when you are running
是的，是的，它的另一个重要部分是环境，所以当您运行时
your transactions your transactions are in the blockchain are surrounded by first of all more
您的交易您的交易在区块链中被首先包围
transactions but also an an environment which is the block the block contains a lot of information
交易，也是一个环境，该环境是该块包含大量信息的块
that can affect the outcome of your transaction.
这可能会影响您的交易结果。
For example, you can read the timestamp of the block
例如，您可以读取块的时间戳
that you're currently executing on,
您目前正在执行
or the preferendow, which is something that comes
或偏爱，这是来的
from the consensus layer and gives you some pseudo-randomness
从共识层中，给您一些伪随机性
as input to your contract.
作为您合同的输入。
Also, the block number, for example, that's very important.
另外，例如，块号非常重要。
You can also get previous block caches,
您也可以获取以前的块scaches，
as well as, for example, a total gas limit.
例如，总气体限制。
If you want to limit how much your test executes,
如果要限制测试执行多少，
you're going to set up a smaller or bigger gas limit.
您将设置越来越多的气体限制。
We have some tests where we bump up this gas
我们有一些测试，我们在这里增加了这种气体
to a very large number
数量很大
just because we want to check
只是因为我们想检查
if any contract takes too long to execute, for example.
例如，如果任何合同需要太长执行。
And also the base fee,
以及基本费用，
because the base fee is very important
因为基本费用非常重要
because even if you are not executing something that requires a big transaction fee,
因为即使您不执行需要大笔交易费用的东西，
you still want to make sure that every single client takes the base fee
您仍然想确保每个客户都需要基本费用
and calculates the correct fee for every transaction that you are testing for.
并计算您要测试的每笔交易的正确费用。
Also, the hard fork activation times is very important also
另外，硬叉激活时间也非常重要
because when we are testing for a new fork,
因为当我们测试新叉时
The most common setup scenario is that we set up an environment where the fork is going to be activated at some end blocks in the future.
最常见的设置方案是，我们设置了一个环境，将来将在某些最终区块中激活叉子。
I'm going to give a very specific example.
我将举一个非常具体的例子。
In the case of the blocks, for example, you are not supposed to be able to run block transactions before the Cancun fork is activated.
例如，对于块，您不应该在激活cancun fork之前运行块交易。
it. So in the environment for this specific test, we set up a fork activation time in the future,
它。因此，在此特定测试的环境中，我们将来设置了一个叉子激活时间，
and then we send the transaction, for example, and then we verify that the block containing
然后我们发送交易，例如，然后验证包含的块
this transaction is correctly rejected by the execution clients. This is just a small example,
执行客户端正确拒绝了此交易。这只是一个小例子，
but there are a ton of ways where you can test a lot of interesting combinations and activation
但是，有很多方法可以测试许多有趣的组合和激活
scenarios with this, with these variables. And that's, that's why the environment is very,
与此变量有关的方案。这就是为什么环境非常
very important for the, for the, for the preparation of the test. And the third one,
对于准备测试非常重要。第三个
this is transactions, right? Is that this is basically the most, most important one.
这是交易，对吗？是这基本上是最重要的，最重要的。
If you don't have a transaction that you're testing with, basically you're not going to
如果您没有正在测试的交易，那么基本上您不会去
execute anything. Every single execution of an EMASmart contract starts with a transaction.
执行任何操作。 EMASMART合同的每个执行都始于交易。
So this is a very important part of the test that we write.
因此，这是我们编写的测试中非常重要的部分。
Most likely, when you're writing a test, you are sending your transaction to a smart contract that you know it's going to execute some important piece of code.
最有可能的是，当您撰写测试时，您将交易发送到智能合约，您知道它将执行一些重要的代码。
You're never going to send just like a transaction just to send Ether from one account to other because there's nothing interesting going on.
您永远不会像交易一样发送只是为了将以太从一个帐户发送到另一个帐户，因为没有什么有趣的事情发生。
But yeah, you're going to set up, with the help of the pre-state and the environment,
但是，是的，您将在预状态和环境的帮助下建立
you're going to set up an interesting transaction where your execution of this transaction is
您将建立一个有趣的交易，在此交易中执行
going to cause something interesting in the blockchain.
将在区块链中引起有趣的东西。
And that's how your test will work.
这就是您的测试的工作方式。
I say transaction and transactions because we have different kinds of tests.
我说交易和交易是因为我们有不同的测试。
I'm going to go into a little bit more detail, but basically we can have tests where just
我要详细介绍一些细节，但基本上我们可以进行测试
transaction is interesting for us, and this is to test very specific EVM executions in the chain.
交易对我们来说很有趣，这是测试链中非常具体的EVM执行。
And we also have a test with multiple transactions which is equal to a block filled with many
而且我们还进行了一项测试，该测试的多项交易等于填充了许多交易
transactions. This is when we are going to test the full blockchain functionality.
交易。这是我们要测试完整的区块链功能的时候。
And lastly, but not less important, is the post state. When we are designing a test it's very
最后，但同样重要的是邮政状态。当我们设计测试时，它非常
it's very important that after you set up the pre-stated environment transactions,
非常重要的是，在设置了预言的环境交易之后，
you also want to know exactly what you are expecting
您还想确切知道您的期望
to happen in the accounts of the blockchain.
发生在区块链的帐户中。
So for example, if you set up a smart contract
因此，例如，如果您设置了智能合约
and the smart contract is supposed to write something
智能合约应该写一些东西
into the storage of the smart contract,
进入智能合约的存储，
you expect a zero to go from zero to one,
您期望零从零变为一个，
then this is the place where you're going to put that in the post-it.
然后，这是您将其放入邮政的地方。
The post it contains all the list of the interesting accounts that you're calling with your transactions
它包含您正在使用交易的所有有趣帐户的列表
and also all the interesting storage values that you want to check after your transaction has executed.
而且，交易执行后，您要检查的所有有趣的存储值。
Very important.
非常重要。
And it's also very important to know exactly what to look for.
确切地知道要寻找什么也很重要。
When you're writing a test, you are not writing a good test unless you really know what the outcome should be.
当您编写测试时，除非您真的知道结果应该是什么，否则您不会编写良好的测试。
This is part of the setup and the verification, basically, at the end of the execution of
这是设置的一部分，基本上是在执行结束时验证
the test.
测试。
I will go into a little bit more detail on how we use all these inputs to generate a
我将详细介绍我们如何使用所有这些输入来生成一个
test and how we verify it against the clients in a little bit.
测试以及我们如何在一点点对客户验证它。
I don't know, Mario, if you have any questions so far.
我不知道，马里奥，如果您到目前为止有任何疑问。
If not, I can just go continue.
如果没有，我可以继续。
Yeah. Okay. So all of these inputs that we have into the EVM tests, they are meaningless unless
是的。好的。因此，我们在EVM测试中拥有的所有这些输入，除非
we have something to execute them with. So this is a process that is called test filling. So once
我们有一些可以执行的。因此，这是一个称为测试填充的过程。所以一次
We have written all of our inputs.
我们已经写了所有的意见。
We have the state that we want to execute.
我们有要执行的状态。
We have the smart contracts that have the correct code and everything that we want to execute.
我们拥有具有正确代码和要执行的所有内容的智能合约。
We still have to somehow apply the state transition, which is the moment where you convert the pre-state and the transaction into a post-it.
我们仍然必须以某种方式应用状态过渡，这是您将预状态和交易转换为邮政的时刻。
And this is a process that is done in many different ways.
这是一个以许多不同方式完成的过程。
but it is important because
但这很重要，因为
when we have a test
当我们有测试时
we have test source code
我们有测试源代码
which is written in JSON or Python
用json或python写的
depending on the repository that you're using
取决于您正在使用的存储库
but the output is always going to be
但是输出将永远是
a JSON output
JSON输出
that's what we use
那就是我们使用的
and it's going to be consumable by every single client
每个客户都将消耗
and this is a process called test filling
这是一个称为测试填充的过程
This process of converting the test design definition into something that is actually consumable and verifiable in each of the clients.
将测试设计定义转换为每个客户中实际消耗和可验证的东西的过程。
Very important process.
非常重要的过程。
I'm going to explain a little bit in the following slides how it is specifically done, how we do it.
我将在以下幻灯片中解释一下它的专门完成方式，我们如何做。
and yeah um yeah also more important um this process of filling is is very different from
是的，嗯，更重要的是，嗯，填充过程与
the unit testing that is performed um by all the clients every every every piece of code um can do
所有客户都可以执行的所有客户都可以执行的单元测试UM可以做
their own unit testing and this is a very common practice when you're developing software and
他们自己的单元测试，这是您开发软件和
The Ethereum clients do use unit testing to test their execution clients and the consensus clients,
以太坊客户确实使用单元测试来测试其执行客户和共识客户，
but the important quality of a test fixture that we have filled is that this can be consumed
但是我们填充的测试固定装置的重要质量是可以消费
by any client. So we generate a test once, and then we can execute it across all of the clients
由任何客户。因此，我们一次生成一次测试，然后我们可以在所有客户端执行它
and verify that none of them have any discrepancies between them. This is very
并验证它们之间没有任何差异。这是非常
important to keep the consensus running. If we relied on writing unit tests for every single
保持共识运行很重要。如果我们依靠每一个的编写单元测试
of the clients, the unit test would definitely be different. So, when we are filling a test and
在客户中，单位测试肯定会有所不同。因此，当我们填写测试时
we create the fixtures it means also that we are sure that the execution client is consuming
我们创建固定装置，这也意味着我们确定执行客户端正在消耗
exactly the same test. This is very important for consensus.
完全相同的测试。这对于共识非常重要。
Okay, so yeah let me see. Yeah, okay so
好吧，是的，让我看看。是的，好吧
this is a small diagram which shows just the
这是一个小图，仅显示
gist of how we do a single state test.
要点我们如何进行单个状态测试。
in the in the in the for the evm testing and we start with what what i already described is the
在为EVM测试中的IN中，我们从我已经描述的内容开始
pre-state you have all the smart contracts all the balances and the code and the storage that you need
预期您拥有所有智能合同，所有余额，代码和所需的存储
for for for your for your test you combine that with a single transaction which has
为了进行测试，您将其与单个交易结合在一起
a in account source an account destination some value which could be either zero or something
A帐户源帐户目的地某些值可能为零或某物的值
some gas and some data.
一些气体和一些数据。
And when you combine that, you will get the post-date,
当您结合起来时，您将获得日期，
which is possibly creation of new smart contracts,
这可能是创建新的智能合约，
some modified balances, some new or modified,
一些修改后的余额，一些新的或修改的余额，
well, not modified code, new code or modified,
好吧，不是修改的代码，新代码或修改的，
yeah, this is incorrect.
是的，这是不正确的。
Not modified code, it's impossible.
没有修改的代码，这是不可能的。
New code or modified storage, yeah, that's it.
是的，是的，就是这样。
and sell the strokes and all that stuff,
并出售中风和所有东西，
you can have everything of that.
您可以拥有一切。
The important part is that on the pre-state,
重要的是，在预状态下，
you have to set up a smart contract
您必须建立智能合同
that performs some interesting things.
这会执行一些有趣的事情。
And that's going to be the destination of your transaction.
这将是您交易的目的地。
Otherwise, it's not going to execute anything meaningful
否则，它不会执行任何有意义的事情
and you're not really testing anything.
而且您并没有真正测试任何东西。
Also, the transaction, for example,
另外，交易，例如
if it's possible that the destination of the transaction
如果有可能交易的目的地
is not a smart contract,
不是明智的合同，
but the creation of a smart contract,
但是创建智能合约，
that's also possible.
这也是可能的。
And then the data that you put in this transaction
然后您投入此交易的数据
executes in the way of init code.
以初始代码的方式执行。
So that's also interesting.
所以这也很有趣。
So if you can put some interesting init code,
因此，如果您可以放一些有趣的初始代码，
it's another way of testing
这是另一种测试方式
that your smart contract was created in the correct way.
您的智能合约是以正确的方式创建的。
and also the modified balances,
还有修改的余额，
the new created code is very important here also
新创建的代码在这里也很重要
and the modified storage if necessary.
以及必要时修改的存储。
Most importantly, we use what's called the stage root
最重要的是，我们使用所谓的舞台根
to make this verification.
进行此验证。
And the stage root is, as we explained earlier,
正如我们之前所解释的那样，舞台根是
the state is what contains the smart contracts, everything,
国家是包含智能合约，一切，
but the root is like this cryptographic computation
但是根就像这个加密计算
that commits and securely commits all the contents of the state
施加并安全地提交了国家的所有内容
into a single number it's a very big number basically 32 bytes of information that is very
单个数字，这是一个非常大的数字，基本上是32个字节的信息
difficult to have two different states that commit into the same uh into the same number this is what
很难拥有两个不同的状态，这些状态将相同的UH变成相同的数字，这就是什么
makes uh the blockchain secure and so given that um that precondition we can assume that if two
使UH区块链安全，因此鉴于这样的前提条件，我们可以假设如果两个
execution clients we you give them this the same pre-state the same transaction you also can know
执行客户端，我们给他们的预期与您也相同的交易相同
that you expect the same state root difference at the end.
您期望结束时具有相同的状态根差。
If you compare two execution clients
如果比较两个执行客户端
and they give you two different state root,
它们给了您两个不同的状态根，
that means one of them, or maybe a test also it's incorrect.
这意味着其中一个，或者也许是测试也是不正确的。
And this is the way that,
这就是
this is the simplest way of testing devian.
这是测试Devian的最简单方法。
We also have fuzzy differential state testing, very similar.
我们也有模糊的差分状态测试，非常相似。
similar. The main difference is that we have a tool which is called FuzzyEVM, which is
相似的。主要区别是我们有一个称为fuzzyevm的工具，
written by one of the developers of the GoEthereum client. And the way that this works is that
由Goethereum客户的开发人员之一撰写。而这种工作的方式是
instead of having an unknown smart contract that we designed to hit some specific code
我们没有拥有未知的智能合约，我们旨在达到一些特定的代码
path in the execution clients. In this case, the fussiness comes in the way of what the code
执行客户端中的路径。在这种情况下，烦恼以代码的方式出现
contains. So you let the code being fussed into the lock, into the pre-set of the chain,
包含。因此，您将代码大惊
and then you create a transaction that specifically the destination is that code,
然后，您创建了一个特定目的地的交易，是该代码，
it's that FOSS smart contract.
就是那个智能合同。
Then since we don't know exactly
然后因为我们不知道
what the outcome of that contract will be
该合同的结果将是什么
because it's FOSS it's gonna have very stochastic
因为它是福斯，它将具有非常随机的
or random behavior.
或随机行为。
You're gonna maybe set storage
您可能会设置存储空间
that you don't expect it to set.
您不希望它设定。
The way that we verify this kind of test
我们验证这种测试的方式
is that we pass the stage route to different
是我们通过舞台路线
and we compare that between different clients.
我们将其比较不同的客户。
So if we have the same first smart contract,
因此，如果我们有相同的第一张智能合约，
the same transaction, the same pre-state,
相同的交易，同一预状态，
and we get a different state route
我们得到了不同的州路线
on two different EVM clients,
在两个不同的EVM客户端，
that means there's a mistake, there's something wrong.
这意味着有一个错误，有问题。
And then you can verify it and see exactly
然后您可以验证它，然后确切查看
by examining the trace of the execution
通过检查执行的痕迹
to know exactly what happened,
确切知道发生了什么，
and then you can find bugs this way.
然后，您可以通过这种方式找到错误。
um yeah and we also have uh blockchain blockchain testing so the previous ones were based on we have
嗯，是的，我们也进行了UH区块链区块链测试，因此以前的基于我们的区块链测试
like a pre-state we have a single transaction and we have a very specific execution that's going to
像预状态一样，我们有一次交易，我们有一个非常具体的执行
happen and we but we also can have a full block testing which means that you also have like the
发生了，我们也可以进行完整的块测试，这意味着您也喜欢
pre-state which is the smart contracts balances code and search and whatever and you put them in
智能合约均衡代码和搜索以及其他任何东西，然后将它们放入
the genesis that you are going to instantiate your blockchain with. Then you start feeding blocks,
您将使用实例化区块链的创世纪。然后，您开始喂食块，
each one with transactions and also header values and also more information that comprises the block.
每个都有交易和标题值，还包括构成块的更多信息。
And then you start feeding the entire block into the execution client. And then you expect that
然后，您开始将整个块馈入执行客户端。然后你期望
after one or two or many blocks, you expect that the client, if your outcome of the validation
在一个或两个或多个块之后，您希望客户，如果您的验证结果
is that every single block that you feed into your test,
是您进食测试的每个块，
that you designed in your test is supposed to be correct,
您在测试中设计的应该是正确的，
then the expectation is that the execution client
那么期望是执行客户端
consumes all of these blocks
消耗所有这些块
and you check the chain head of the execution client,
然后您检查执行客户端的连锁头，
you must find here the block that you expected it to be.
您必须在这里找到您期望的块。
If for some reason, let's say in this diagram,
如果出于某种原因，请在此图中说，
block number two was deemed invalid
第二块被认为是无效的
by one of the execution clients
由一个执行客户之一
because they have a faulty check somewhere.
因为他们在某处的检查有故障。
That means that the chain head
这意味着连锁头
is not going to correspond to block number two
不会对应于第二个块
and then you get an error.
然后您会遇到错误。
This is very important
这很重要
because not everything that we check
因为不是我们检查的一切
on the execution clients is part of the EVM execution.
在执行上，客户端是EVM执行的一部分。
We also check other values
我们还检查其他值
that are resulting of the execution of previous blocks.
这是执行先前块的结果。
For example, 1559, which is the base fee,
例如，1559年，这是基本费用，
you have the base fee of the block,
您有块的基本费用，
and this is calculated based on previous transactions
这是根据先前的交易计算的
of the previous block.
上一个块。
So if there was some client
所以如果有一些客户
that had a faulty calculation of 5059, the base fee,
计算错误的5059，基本费用，
then you will get a rejection somewhere in here, for example.
例如，您将在这里的某个地方得到拒绝。
and then your chain head will not match
然后您的连锁头将不匹配
to the last block of your test,
到测试的最后一个块，
then you will have found a bug.
然后，您会发现一个错误。
Then you also check the post date,
然后，您还检查发布日期，
the new smart contracts, the modified balances,
新的智能合约，修改后的余额，
the new code, the modified storage, everything.
新代码，修改的存储，所有内容。
You check that everything is in place
您检查一切都到位
because even after correctly consuming all of the blocks
因为即使在正确消耗所有块之后
up to the end block,
到末端块，
you could still have some bugs somewhere
您仍然可以在某个地方有一些错误
where the storage for some reason
出于某种原因存储的地方
does not respond correctly from the execution line.
无法从执行行正确响应。
That's very, very, it's not very common
非常非常常见
because normally when you check the chain head,
因为通常在检查链头时，
you also checked the state root,
您还检查了状态根，
which means that the descriptographic commitment
这意味着描述性承诺
that we talked about previously.
我们之前谈到了。
And that means that you have your storage correctly.
这意味着您的存储空间正确。
So these kinds of checks are just sanity checks,
因此，这些检查只是理智检查，
extra checks.
额外的支票。
but yeah, the basic gist is that
但是，是的，基本要旨是
all the blocks were consumed
所有的块被消耗
because the client is correct
因为客户是正确的
and we also have the other way of checking
我们还有其他检查方式
which is that you design your test
这是您设计考试
with one invalid block at some point
在某个时候有一个无效的块
for example, let's take the example
例如，让我们以榜样
of the 1559 again,
在1559年再次
which is, let's say that you
这是，假设你
deliberately put an invalid value
故意提出无效的价值
into the base fee of a block
进入块的基本费用
and then you feed that block
然后你喂那个块
to the client,
给客户，
then you expect the client
那你期望客户
to reject this block.
拒绝这个块。
So what will happen is that
所以会发生的是
the block gets rejected.
块被拒绝。
That's one check.
那是一张支票。
Then you go back into the client
然后您回到客户
and you say, okay,
你说，好吧，
what was the last block that I gave you?
我给你的最后一个街区是什么？
That was correct.
那是正确的。
Then you check that again
然后您再次检查
because in this case it's block number two.
因为在这种情况下，它是第二个块。
That was the last block.
那是最后一个街区。
Then you check the post-it and everything.
然后，您检查帖子和所有内容。
And here the post-it becomes important
在这里，帖子变得很重要
because if you feed an invalid block,
因为如果您喂养一个无效的块，
you expect that the post-it
您期望邮政
or the contracts living in the client
或居住在客户的合同
are not belonging to the invalid block.
不属于无效块。
So in this case, this check is actually more important.
因此，在这种情况下，此检查实际上更为重要。
It's also very important to know exactly how the client failed.
确切了解客户是如何失败也非常重要。
It's very important when you are designing one of these negative tests that you are completely sure that there's no other way that the client could fail.
当您设计这些负面测试之一时，您完全确定客户可能会失败，这一点非常重要。
for example if okay again if you are designing a test for 1559 and you want to put an invalid
例如，如果您正在设计1559的测试，并且要放置一个无效的
um value in in the base fee but you forget to update the block hatch with this modified value
基本费用中的值，但您忘记使用此修改值更新块舱口
with this modified value it would mean that um that the client is still going to correctly
有了这个修改的值，这意味着um客户仍将正确
correctly reject your block but not because of the base fee value that you modified but
正确拒绝您的块，但不是因为您修改的基本费用值
instead because of the block hash.
而是因为块哈希。
So that's an invalid test
这是一个无效的测试
because you didn't make sure that every other field,
因为您没有确定其他每个字段，所以
what you were testing was correct.
您正在测试的是正确的。
So if you have,
所以，如果有的话，
so this is very important when saying a test
因此，这在说考试时非常重要
and you have to always make sure.
而且您必须始终确保。
This is something that it's very easy to slip in here
这是很容易溜进这里很容易的东西
to write a test
写测试
and then you think you correctly wrote your test
然后您认为您正确编写了测试
and then realizing later then,
然后稍后意识到，
okay, I didn't change this, and the client was passing the test,
好吧，我没有改变这个，客户正在通过测试，
but there was a fault somewhere that I didn't detect
但是我没有发现某个地方的错
because the client still rejected the block
因为客户仍然拒绝了块
because my block was not correctly designed.
因为我的块没有正确设计。
My test was not correctly designed.
我的测试未正确设计。
Yeah.
是的。
Any questions so far?
到目前为止有任何问题吗？
There is a discussion going on.
正在进行讨论。
Maybe, guys, I will give you a second if you want to ask a question.
也许，伙计们，如果您想问一个问题，我会给您一秒钟。
But otherwise it's pretty clear.
但是否则很清楚。
Thank you so much, Mario.
非常感谢，马里奥。
It's great.
这很棒。
People were discussing, like, just some stuff I was able to answer.
人们正在讨论我能回答的一些事情。
Yeah.
是的。
I think we'll get to questions later.
我想我们稍后会提出问题。
All right.
好的。
Cool.
凉爽的。
Okay, so now to the actual test filling part of the test.
好的，现在要进行测试的实际测试填充部分。
We're going to start with the first repository that we have.
我们将从拥有的第一个存储库开始。
This is the Ethereum test repo which has existed since the inception of Ethereum, almost nine
这是自以太坊成立以来已经存在的以太坊测试库，近九个
years ago.
几年前。
And this is the first test-filling framework that was produced by the Ethereum community.
这是以太坊社区生产的第一个测试框架。
It's basically the source files of the tests are simple JSON files or YAML, which is the
基本上，测试的源文件是简单的JSON文件或YAML，这是
source code.
源代码。
This is the part where you design your pre-states, your storage, your code, your smart contracts,
这是您设计预状态，存储，代码，智能合约的部分
everything you put it in there.
你把它放在那里的一切。
This all goes into a JSON file or a YAML file.
这一切都进入了JSON文件或YAML文件。
It provides very simple parameterization
它提供非常简单的参数化
in the sense that you can set up multiple transactions
从某种意义上说，您可以设置多个交易
to operate on top of the same pre-state,
要在同一预状态的顶部操作，
and then you expect a different outcome
然后您期望有不同的结果
depending on the transaction.
取决于交易。
And then you can also check all that
然后您也可以检查所有
in a compact JSON format.
以紧凑的JSON格式。
and these tests are written in C++.
这些测试以C ++编写。
I'm sorry, the test filler is called retest it.
抱歉，测试填充剂称为重新测试。
It's written in C++.
它用C ++编写。
What retest it is basically you have your JSON input,
基本上是您的JSON输入，是什么重新测试，
you have retest it, and then you call retest it,
您已经重新测试了它，然后将其调用，
and then it consumes the JSON.
然后它消耗了JSON。
it calls go it through actually to fill it this and then at the end you have a
它打电话给它实际填充它，然后最后您有一个
fixture that every single client can consume then you can check for
每个客户都可以消耗的固定装置，然后您可以检查
invalidity in any of the any of the clients
任何客户中的任何一个无效
and we have the newer execution specters this was just developed over the over
而且我们有较新的执行幽灵，这刚刚开发了
the course of last year and the previous year also.
去年和上一年的过程。
The main difference is that we have Python source code.
主要区别在于我们具有Python源代码。
So the source of the tests, this is where you define your pre-state and everything.
因此，测试的来源是您定义预状态和所有内容的地方。
This is all in Python.
这一切都在Python中。
And it provides simple to complex parameterization because it's powered by PyTest.
它提供了简单至复杂的参数化，因为它是由Pytest供电的。
So we have all of the PyTest tools are at disposal to make different parameterization
因此，我们所有的PYTest工具都可以使用，以进行不同的参数化
of different tests.
不同的测试。
And this allows a lot of flexibility
这允许很大的灵活性
and it's very efficient
而且非常有效
on just writing a single input
仅写单个输入
and then you just pass
然后你只通过
a lot of parameters,
很多参数，
a lot of values
很多价值观
for the parameterization.
用于参数化。
It will generate a ton of tests for you.
它将为您产生大量测试。
It's really, really convenient.
真的很方便。
It can get really complex.
它会变得非常复杂。
So we're still defining,
因此，我们仍在定义
we're still at that point
我们还在那时
where we're defining
我们在哪里定义
how much complexity do we want the tests to be.
我们希望测试有多少复杂性。
So it's a really nice framework overall.
因此，这是一个非常不错的框架。
The downside is that, as retested also,
不利的一面是，正如重新测试一样
this still also requires an actual client implementation
这仍然需要实际的客户实施
to be able to fill the tests
能够填写测试
because of the transition function.
由于过渡函数。
This is only because we don't have
这只是因为我们没有
the transition function implemented in Python so far,
到目前为止，在Python中实现的过渡函数，
but there's a work in progress to have
但是正在进行的工作
the entire Python specification
整个Python规范
written in a script that is called yields,
用称为收益的脚本编写，
which is the Ethereum execution layer spec.
这是以太坊执行层规格。
And this will, in the future,
这将来会
will be used to serve as the actual client representation,
将被用作实际客户代表，
but not today.
但不是今天。
Okay.
好的。
This is the, this are the inner workings of how the execution spec test.
这就是执行规范测试的内在工作。
This is very similar, both in retest it and execution spec test.
在重新测试和执行规格测试中，这都是非常相似的。
So I'm going to go over this point on how it works internally.
因此，我将介绍它在内部的工作方式。
It's very simple, actually.
实际上，这很简单。
it's the framework, as I said earlier, it starts with some Python tests.
正如我之前所说，这是框架，它从一些Python测试开始。
This test you can create one for every single EIP or several for several EIPs or you can
此测试您可以为每个EIP创建一个或几个EIP的测试，也可以
write many for many forks, for example.
例如，为许多叉子写许多。
The way that we are working right now is that we have different folders where our Python
我们现在正在工作的方式是我们有不同的文件夹
tests live, one for every fork.
测试现场测试，每个叉子一个。
fork so for example we started from frontier and we go all the way up to cancun and cancun
叉子所以例如，我们从Frontier开始，然后一直到坎昆和坎昆
at the moment contains all of the 48404 tests all of the beacon root contract tests and everything
目前包含所有48404测试，所有标签根合同测试和所有测试
all all of that it's uh very well organized uh this is something i really like from different
所有这一切都很好地组织了嗯，这是我真正喜欢的东西
in your repository and you start from that you have a you you start with your python test where
在您的存储库中，您就开始了您的一个，从python测试开始
you write all your pre-states, your transactions, you actually have written the parameterization
您写所有的预状态，交易，实际上已经写了参数化
or everything.
或一切。
And then, when you execute this, to execute this, what it uses is the fill command that
然后，当您执行此操作时，执行此操作，它使用的是填充命令
we have in this repository.
我们有这个存储库。
You specify the fill command to what test you want to execute it at the moment, and
您将填充命令指定为您目前要执行的测试，并且
then it will go in, execute the Python code.
然后它将进入，执行Python代码。
The important part is that it has two dependencies, well, three.
重要的部分是它具有两个依赖关系，三个。
The bottom one is a little bit less important,
底部有点不重要，
but the two ones on the top are,
但是顶部的两个是
and especially the top one is very important.
尤其是顶部非常重要。
So when you're filling tests
因此，当您填写测试时
and you get to the point where you want to execute a transaction,
然后，您要达到要执行交易的地步，
but you don't know how to do this because you're running Python,
但是您不知道该怎么做，因为您正在运行Python，
you don't have the actual logic of the execution client,
您没有执行客户端的实际逻辑，
what you do is you spawn up this go Ethereum subcommand,
您要做的是催生这个Go Ethereum子命令，
sub-command, which is called EVM.
子命令，称为EVM。
And then EVM transition is actually EVM TA10.
然后EVM过渡实际上是EVM TA10。
What you give to this command is just all the pre-state
您对此命令的提供只是所有预状态
and the transactions and the environment,
以及交易和环境，
and then it will spit out what the result
然后它将吐出结果
of the execution is,
执行是
including the execution of every single transaction
包括执行每个交易
that you gave it.
你给了它。
This is important because it's a very back and forth
这很重要，因为它是一个来回的
process, feeding tests, if you have one single test that
过程，进食测试，如果您有一个测试
executes 10 blocks, you will be calling this EVM
执行10个块，您将调用此EVM
transition tool 10 times.
过渡工具10次。
It's very efficient.
这非常有效。
It's not...
它不是...
But we have more solutions in the way to make it
但是我们有更多的解决方案来实现它
even more efficient, because we basically call
甚至更有效，因为我们基本上致电
once, two, or three times
一次，两次或三次
every single test.
每个测试。
So it gets quite consuming,
因此，它变得非常消耗，
quite CPU consuming.
CPU消耗相当多。
The second dependency that we have
我们拥有的第二个依赖性
is Solidity.
是坚固的。
And this is less so
而且这是不那么
because most of our tests
因为我们的大多数测试
inside of our framework,
在我们的框架内，
we have every single opcode
我们有每个opcode
that the EVM has.
EVM拥有的。
And so you don't really need
所以你真的不需要
to write Solidity.
写坚固。
And Solidity is an excellent language to write smart contracts.
坚固性是写智能合约的出色语言。
But the problem with us is that we normally have to focus
但是我们的问题是我们通常必须集中精力
on single opcodes that we are testing.
在我们正在测试的单一opcodes上。
So in the case that Solidity makes some optimization
因此，在坚固性进行一些优化的情况下
to what we are expecting to see in the bytecode
我们期望在字节码中看到的
that goes into a smart contract, that is not good.
这陷入了智能合同，这不是很好。
because if it optimizes out some very important opcode
因为如果它优化了一些非常重要的操作码
that we are actually testing,
我们实际上正在测试，
when we are filling that test,
当我们填写该测试时，
it's going to make the test unreliable.
这将使测试不可靠。
It's simply not going to work
根本不工作
because the opcode that you're testing is not there.
因为您要测试的操作码不存在。
It's not executed.
它没有执行。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
So we only use Solidity when we have very complex code
因此，我们只有在我们的代码非常复杂时就使用坚固
that we cannot do with bytecode writing.
我们无法处理字节码写作。
And it's not actually bytecode writing.
而且它实际上不是字节上的写作。
is I will show an example in the source code in a bit,
我会在源代码中显示一个示例吗？
just for you guys to see how we write this.
只是让你们看看我们如何写这篇文章。
But yes, it's less and less used by us.
但是，是的，我们越来越少地使用它。
We also have the other input is the EIPs,
我们也有另一个输入是EIPS，
the repository actually.
存储库实际上。
This is the primary source of the specification
这是规范的主要来源
that we use to write the test.
我们用来编写测试。
So whenever we are writing a test,
因此，每当我们写测试时，
we don't go to the goetherium's code,
我们不去Goetherium的代码，
we go to the specification.
我们去规格。
And from that, we pull out the test cases.
由此，我们取出了测试用例。
We actually write them from the specification.
实际上，我们从规范中写下它们。
So it's very important to preserve the ideas of the EIPs
因此，保留EIP的想法非常重要
in the source code of the tests.
在测试的源代码中。
And the way that we do this here is that we also,
我们在这里这样做的方式是，我们也
well, one is the tester, the test writer.
好吧，一个是测试人员，测试作者。
they are going into the EIP and they are copying or bringing or whatever the formulas,
他们进入EIP，正在复制或带来或任何公式，
whatever that is describing there, but also they bring the checksum and the version of the EIP.
无论那里描述了什么，但它们也带来了校验和EIP的版本。
And this is important because during the development process of any fork,
这很重要，因为在任何叉子的开发过程中，
it's really common that the EIPs change from time to time.
EIP不时改变确实很常见。
So this is like a safe measure that we use to make sure that, okay, we pulled this logic or information from the EIP or this idea from the EIP.
因此，这就像一种安全的措施，我们用来确保，好吧，我们从EIP或EIP中汲取了此逻辑或信息。
Are we sure that we are working on this new expression?
我们确定我们正在研究这个新表达式吗？
Because then the EIP changes and then the execution client goes and implements a new version and our tests start failing.
因为这样，EIP就会更改，然后执行客户端进行并实现新版本，我们的测试开始失败。
And they come to us and say, what did you write?
他们来找我们说，你写了什么？
then we have a proof that we wrote for the EAP,
然后，我们有一个证明我们为EAP撰写的证据，
but at a previous version.
但是在以前的版本中。
So then the processes are just to go update
因此，这些过程只是为了更新
to the newest version,
对于最新版本，
but then we have failsafe here
但是我们在这里有失败的安全
just to make sure that we are writing
只是为了确保我们正在写
for some version of the EAP.
对于某些版本的EAP。
Yeah, after the fill command is executed,
是的，执行填充命令后，
we get the output.
我们得到输出。
And this is the important part.
这是重要的部分。
These are the fixtures.
这些是固定装置。
This is very simple.
这很简单。
it's not very simple JSON file, but it's very readable.
这不是很简单的JSON文件，但是非常可读。
There's nothing complex in the JSON files.
JSON文件中没有什么复杂的。
It's basically just the output of the test.
基本上只是测试的输出。
And there are two flavors.
还有两种口味。
It's the, well, three flavors is the state test,
这是国家测试，是三种口味，
which is the first one that I described over here.
这是我在这里描述的第一个。
The state test, we have a format specific for this,
国家测试，我们对此有一种特定格式，
and we have another format specific for this.
我们有另一种特定于此的格式。
and the third format is which is this same format the blockchain format but we that we use to consume
第三格式是区块链格式相同的格式，但我们用来消耗的格式
in hive which is a tool that i will explain a little bit further in the presentation and yeah
在Hive中，这是我将在演示文稿中进一步解释的工具，是的
the important part here is that this is the actual input to the clients and this is how we test
这里重要的部分是这是对客户的实际输入，这就是我们测试的方式
clients because the client goes and consumes this json and if it finds some something that it's that
客户是因为客户去了并消耗了这个JSON，并且如果发现某些东西就是
it could not consume or when it consumed it it found a different result that means there's a
它不能消费或消耗它时，发现了一个不同的结果，这意味着有一个
difference there's a there's a there's an error somewhere and this is how we find the bugs
差异有一个地方有一个错误，这就是我们找到错误的方式
in declines at least for the evm part of the testing um i will explain a little bit further
在测试的EVM部分中，我将进一步解释
uh the in in the in the presentation about hive and but the the gist on why we need it is because
嗯，在有关蜂巢的演讲中，但是我们为什么需要它的要旨是因为
there are always two methods of consumption of the blocks
总是有两种消费块的方法
in every single execution client.
在每个执行客户端中。
So one is the raw format.
所以一种是原始格式。
You have the block, the actual block,
您有块，实际块，
which is formed into RLP, which is an encoding method.
它形成为RLP，这是一种编码方法。
And this gets broadcasted through the peer-to-peer network.
这是通过对等网络广播的。
So when you're syncing, this is what you're getting.
因此，当您同步时，这就是您得到的。
But in the other case, when we use Hive,
但是在另一种情况下，当我们使用蜂巢时，
we feed the execution client via the engine API,
我们通过引擎API喂食执行客户端，
which is the engine API is basically just a method of communication
这是引擎API基本上只是一种通信方法
between the execution client and the consensus layer.
在执行客户端和共识层之间。
So when the actual Ethereum blockchain is running,
因此，当实际以太坊区块链运行时，
we have the consensus client running,
我们正在运行共识客户端，
and it's giving instructions back to the execution client.
它将指令还给执行客户端。
so those instructions are in the form of the engine API directives
因此这些说明是以引擎API指令的形式
and this is what we test here
这就是我们在这里测试的
so when we are filling the tests
因此，当我们填写测试时
the high format contains the actual engine API directives
高格式包含实际的发动机API指令
that are going to come from the consensus client
这些将来自共识客户
so we can be sure that this specific test scenario
因此，我们可以确定这种特定的测试方案
is going to be tested as if it was running on the real blockchain
即将被测试，好像它在实际区块链上运行
Taking into account the difference that comes from the fact that mainnet is very, very large
考虑到主网非常非常大的事实带来的区别
in state terms, and all of the tests that we filled, they are very, very small state
从状态和我们填写的所有测试中，它们都是非常非常小的状态
because otherwise it wouldn't be manageable, but it's more or less the same thing.
因为否则它将不可管理，但或多或​​少是同一件事。
Okay. So, yeah. I wanted to give a little demo on how we actually fill the tests. Let
好的。所以，是的。我想对我们如何真正填写测试进行一些演示。让
me go to the actual repository. By the way, can you still see my screen?
我去实际存储库。顺便说一句，您还能看到我的屏幕吗？
Yes, all good.
是的，一切都很好。
All right, perfect. This is the execution spectas repository, and it's very nicely documented. We
好吧，完美。这是执行镜头存储库，并且记录在非常完美。我们
have this documentation page here that you guys can come and see. The first, we need three things
在这里有这个文档页面，你们可以来看看。首先，我们需要三件事
to run this. Well, and the Paroxy that you need Python installed. You need Python 3.10,
运行这个。好吧，以及您需要安装的python的疟原虫。您需要Python 3.10，
I think yes 3.10 and we also need to have compiled EVM and Solidity so I'm not
我认为是3.10，我们还需要编译EVM和坚固性，所以我不是
I'm not gonna go over how to compile go go Ethereum and or Solidity you can
我不会介绍如何编译去以太坊，或者你可以
assume that it's very it you go to the README and go to go Ethereum's repository
假设您要去读书我去以太坊的存储库去了
and you can you can compile it but yeah the first approach is that you come to
您可以将其编译，但是是的，第一种方法是您来
this repository and then you can clone the entire repository and just git clone
此存储库，然后您可以克隆整个存储库，而只是git克隆
this and you can get a copy of this in your in your PC and let me just show you
这个，您可以在您的PC中获得此副本，让我向您展示
what the repository looks like yeah this is this is this comprises the
存储库是的，是的，这是
The repository is comprised by two.
存储库由两个组成。
Let me just, there you go.
让我就在那里。
The repository, let me delete this.
存储库，让我删除此。
And we have two sections of the repository.
我们有两个部分的部分。
The first one is the source code of the framework.
第一个是框架的源代码。
So everything that you find inside of source,
因此，您在来源中找到的所有内容，
it belongs to the code that we use to fill the tests.
它属于我们用来填写测试的代码。
There are no tests here for the Ethereum blockchain.
这里没有针对以太坊区块链的测试。
And then the second part is the tests,
然后第二部分是测试，
also in the root directory.
也在根目录中。
You can start seeing here
您可以在这里开始看到
that you actually start to see some hard forks.
您实际上开始看到一些硬叉。
So we have every single hard fork
所以我们有每一个硬叉
until Cancun is over here.
直到Cancun在这里为止。
And we start from Frontier.
我们从Frontier开始。
And then Homestead, Byzantium, Istanbul,
然后宅基地，拜占庭，伊斯坦布尔，
Parish, the Marish or Paris,
教区，婚姻或巴黎，
and Shanghai and I skipped London and Berlin, but yeah, you get the idea.
上海和我跳过了伦敦和柏林，但是，是的，你明白了。
So if you go into any of these folders, you can see every single test that we have implemented.
因此，如果您进入这些文件夹中的任何一个，则可以看到我们已经实施的每个测试。
Just take into account that this repository started being active since Shanghai.
只要考虑到自上海以来这个存储库就开始活跃。
So for Shanghai, yeah, you will see every single AIP.
因此，对于上海，是的，您将看到每个AIP。
But for example, for Berlin, you will not see that many because it was not active when Berlin came to be.
但是，例如，对于柏林，您不会看到很多，因为柏林来到柏林时并不活跃。
So you will not see all of the full set of tests.
因此，您将看不到所有完整的测试。
Those will, you can find them in the Ethereum test repository.
这些会在以太坊测试存储库中找到它们。
So yeah, let's take a look at just the simplest test that I can think of.
是的，让我们看看我能想到的最简单的测试。
Let's go to one of these tests.
让我们去参加其中一项测试。
And yeah, let's start from the top.
是的，让我们从顶部开始。
Every single test that we write here uses PyTest.
我们在这里编写的每个测试都使用pytest。
It's a framework that we use to fill our tests.
这是我们用来填写测试的框架。
We use a lot of the functionality that PyTest provides for us.
我们使用Pytest为我们提供的许多功能。
Then you can see that we need to write
然后，您可以看到我们需要写
functions for each of the tests that we want to provide.
我们要提供的每个测试的功能。
In this case, we have this very simple test that is called TestDup.
在这种情况下，我们有一个非常简单的测试，称为TestDup。
Its purpose is to, as it is stated here,
它的目的是，如这里所述
it's to test the DUP upcodes,
是测试dup升级，
which are one of the most simple upcodes that exists in DBM.
这是DBM中存在的最简单的升级之一。
It tests DUP 1 through 16.
它测试DUP 1至16。
So it will generate one test for every single DUP upcode.
因此，它将为每个DUP升级生成一个测试。
Yeah, you can see here really nicely how you can,
是的，您可以在这里很好地看到您的方式，
you have the, you can see that the actual meaning
您有，您可以看到实际含义
of each of the upcodes.
每个升级。
But yeah, this test function,
但是，是的，这个测试功能，
it generates one status,
它生成一个状态，
the one that we talked about earlier,
我们之前谈论的那个
the first one.
第一个。
And the reason being is that
原因是
this is purely an EVM test.
这纯粹是EVM测试。
So you can abstract everything away
因此您可以将所有内容抽象
that is on the block
那在街区
and you can stay only with the upcodes
而且您只能呆在
and the EVM execution
和EVM执行
and then you get this test
然后你得到这个测试
because it's the simplest.
因为这是最简单的。
You don't require anything from outside.
您不需要外面任何东西。
to test the dub command um that's that's the main thing uh to keep in mind when you're deciding which
测试配音命令um，这是当您确定哪个时要牢记的主要事情
which format you're going to test with um yeah you you get an environment um and you get the
您要使用哪种格式进行测试，是的，您得到了一个环境，您得到了
pre this is the breed that we have been talking about so the first thing that you have to do is
pre this是我们一直在谈论的品种，所以您要做的第一件事就是
yeah you have to uh you have a common test address which is the source of all of our transactions that
是的，您必须有一个常见的测试地址，这是我们所有交易的来源
that we write.
我们写的。
And this pre, it will contain all of the code also,
而且，它还将包含所有代码，
but it's not filled here.
但这并不是在这里填写。
So at this point, we only set up a test address,
因此，在这一点上，我们仅设置一个测试地址，
which is the source of the transaction,
这是交易的来源，
and we will have an unlimited amount of balance
我们将有无限的平衡
because this will be the source
因为这将是来源
of all the transactions that we send.
我们发送的所有交易。
So it has to have something, right?
所以它必须有东西，对吗？
Then we define the account,
然后我们定义帐户，
the account where we are going to put the code that we are going to work with. This is the main
我们将要使用要使用的代码的帐户。这是主要的
account where the transaction is going to be sent to, and then it will, we are going to start
交易将发送到的帐户，然后将开始，我们将开始
creating the code on top of it, which is this. Let me see if there's anything else. Okay, yeah.
在其上创建代码，这就是这样。让我看看还有其他。好吧，是的。
So yeah, and as you can see, it's, there are three parts to generating this code.
是的，如您所见，这是生成此代码的三个部分。
So the first part is that
所以第一部分是
We're going to create
我们将创建
10, so from 0 to
10，从0到
10, no
10，没有
0x10, which is 16
0x10，是16
Push commands
推送命令
So this is very easy, it's just
所以这很容易，只是
The push command is
推送命令是
Basically just push something
基本上只是推东西
Into the EVMS stack
进入EVMS堆栈
So yeah, the EVMS stack computer
是的，EVMS堆栈计算机
And then you use
然后您使用
The stack for a lot of things
很多东西的堆栈
So the main
所以主
EVM opcode that you're going to use ever writing a test is at least some of the push commands.
您将要使用的EVM操作码至少是一些推送命令。
So in this case, we're using them.
因此，在这种情况下，我们正在使用它们。
We are using the simplest one, which is just push one byte into the stack.
我们使用的是最简单的，它只是将一个字节推入堆栈。
The stack is comprised of 32-byte elements.
该堆栈由32个字节元素组成。
But in this case, we're just pushing one byte.
但是在这种情况下，我们只是在推动一个字节。
So it's going to be 31 zeros, 31 zero bytes, and then one byte, which is defined by this.
因此，将是31个零，31个零字节，然后是一个字节，这是由此定义的。
And if you know Python, you know now that we are going to collect all of this.
而且，如果您知道Python，您现在就知道我们将收集所有这些。
We're going to collect this array or list into a byte code that is going to go here.
我们将将此数组或列表收集到要去此处的字节代码中。
After that, we're going to put or up code that is under testing,
之后，我们将提出或正在进行测试的代码，
which is defined this variable.
定义此变量。
And this variable is special
这个变量很特别
because we define it as the parameters to our test,
因为我们将其定义为测试的参数，所以
as you can see here.
正如您在这里看到的。
And also it's important
而且这很重要
because this is what is being parametrized.
因为这是正在参数化的。
This is one of the most important decorators
这是最重要的装饰器之一
that we use from ByteDest.
我们从最终使用。
Basically just take this parameter
基本上只需使用此参数
that is going to be used down here
这将在这里使用
and then run this function each time for each one of this.
然后每次为此运行此功能。
So the value of this variable is going to change
因此，此变量的价值将改变
in each iteration that this function is executed.
在每个迭代中，都执行此功能。
So the first iteration is going to use the dub1,
因此，第一次迭代将使用dub1，
and the second, dub2, and so on and so forth.
第二，dub2，依此类推。
And that is going to change which value of the bytecode is executed.
这将更改执行字节码的哪个值。
And therefore it's going to change the outcome.
因此，它将改变结果。
of the test.
测试。
Lastly, we're gonna use another
最后，我们要使用另一个
of the most important opcodes that we use,
我们使用的最重要的Opcodes
which is the SsStore.
这是SSStore。
And the SsStore is basically the most used opcode for us
SSStore基本上是我们最常用的OpCode
because this is the way that we save the stuff
因为这是我们保存东西的方式
into the storage of the contract that we are executing it.
进入我们正在执行的合同的存储。
if we don't use this opcode anywhere in our tests,
如果我们在测试中的任何地方都不使用此操作码，
it means either that we are testing something else,
这意味着我们正在测试其他东西，
like an error or something,
像错误之类的东西
or we have written an invalid test, basically.
或者我们基本上已经写了一个无效的测试。
And in this case, what we are doing is, like,
在这种情况下，我们正在做的是，就像
we already have all of these things in the stack,
我们已经把所有这些东西都放在堆栈中了，
in the stack over EVM execution.
在EVM执行的堆栈中。
Then the last step is just to save them.
然后，最后一步只是为了保存它们。
So that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里做的。
we're pushing just one more byte into the stack,
我们只将一个字节推入堆栈，
which is where we're going to save this value here
我们将在这里保存此值
that we pushed previously.
我们以前推了。
And then store it, obviously.
显然，然后存储它。
And we're going to do that for every single stack item
我们将为每个堆栈项目做到这一点
that we have, which is one more.
我们拥有的，这是一个。
No, it's the same.
不，是一样的。
Yeah, and that's going to be stored
是的，这将被存储
when we execute our code.
当我们执行代码时。
Lastly, we have our account set up,
最后，我们设置了帐户，
which has its code, its address and everything.
具有其代码，地址和所有内容。
So we are ready to just put it into the pre-state,
因此，我们准备将其放入预状态中，
which means that when we execute this test
这意味着当我们执行此测试时
and the client consumes this test,
客户会消耗此测试，
it's going to find a pre-state that contains the account.
它将找到包含该帐户的预状态。
So that's very important
所以这很重要
because it's how the transaction is going to be executed
因为这是要执行交易的方式
and it's the destination of the transaction,
这是交易的目的地，
as you can see here.
正如您在这里看到的。
Yes, exactly.
是的，到底是。
So the transaction that we produce in this test
因此，我们在此测试中进行的交易
is a single transaction.
是单个交易。
and the only thing that it matters here
这在这里唯一重要
is that we are sending it to the account
是我们将其发送到帐户
where we put the code that we were writing.
我们放入所写的代码。
Plus all the information, but this is not relevant.
加上所有信息，但这与此无关。
Yeah, basically, and also, lastly,
是的，基本上，最后，最后，
the last thing that we're going to set
我们要设定的最后一件事
is the post date,
是发布日期，
which is what we're going to check
这是我们要检查的
that happened after the execution of the transaction.
这是在执行交易后发生的。
Basically, it just expects that the stack items
基本上，它只是期望堆栈项目
are in the correct position that we stated here.
我们在这里说的是正确的位置。
If you read the description, you will find out how it works.
如果您阅读了描述，您将发现其工作原理。
But yeah, this is basically the last step.
但是，是的，这基本上是最后一步。
The next step is just filling test.
下一步只是填充测试。
What will happen here is that we're going to fill the status
这里会发生什么，我们将填补状态
with all of the ingredients that we set up before.
使用我们之前设置的所有成分。
And it's going to give us a fixture.
这将为我们提供一个固定装置。
So the easiest way just to do that
因此，最简单的方法就是这样做
is going to be that we run the fill command.
是我们运行填充命令。
And so where are we is important.
因此，我们在哪里很重要。
So test frontier upcodes test underscore dub.py.
因此，测试边境升级测试测试下划线Dub.py。
Let's do that.
让我们这样做。
Fill fork Cancun, let's say.
填充叉子坎昆，假设。
and tests
和测试
frontier
边境
what is
是什么
upcodes and test
升级和测试
underscore dub
下划线配音
there you go
你去
so as you can see
如您所见
we generated a ton of tests
我们产生了大量的测试
48 which is
48是
I'll explain that in a bit
我会有点解释
so this means
所以这意味着
that every single test that we run here
我们在这里进行的每个测试
the
这
the execution client in this case,
在这种情况下，执行客户端
because we are filling with this transition tool from geth,
因为我们正在用Geth填充此过渡工具，所以
we are not testing any other client here.
我们在这里没有测试任何其他客户。
We are just using geth to tell us what the outcome should be.
我们只是在使用Geth告诉我们结果应该是什么。
But we have a safe measure here.
但是我们在这里有一个安全的措施。
So if we design or test properly,
因此，如果我们正确设计或测试，
it means that what we put here, it makes sense.
这意味着我们放在这里，这是有道理的。
So if we modify this, let's say,
因此，如果我们修改了这一点，可以说，
let us save this to something else, like 20 or something.
让我们将其保存到其他东西，例如20岁之类的东西。
and let's just run it again to see what happens.
让我们再次运行它，看看会发生什么。
There you go.
你去。
So yeah, it's not...
是的，不是...
Yeah, I put this very, very big.
是的，我把这个非常非常大。
So the thing is here that
所以这里就是
everything that we put here in the post
我们在帖子中放置的一切
is really important for us to make sure
对我们来说真的很重要
that the execution client that we are filling the test with
我们正在使用的执行客户端填写测试
is actually sane.
实际上是理智的。
Otherwise, it would go on and generate tests
否则，它将继续生成测试
that will be consumed by our clients,
这将被我们的客户消费
but it will it will they will fail because the execution client that we used to fill the tests
但这将会失败，因为我们用来填写测试的执行客户端
is faulty so let's go back to the original just to make sure that we fill the test again
是错误的，所以让我们回到原件，以确保我们再次填写测试
and there you go okay and um what's the outcome of this so we now have a new um a new folder let's
而且您可以走了，嗯，这是什么结果，所以我们现在有了一个新的新文件夹，让我们
see yeah there you go so we have this folder which is called this is the output this is the
看到的是，您去了，所以我们有一个称为这是输出的文件夹，这是
fixtures output. And you can see that these are the three formats that we expect here.
固定装置输出。您会看到这些是我们在这里期望的三种格式。
So the first one is the blockchain test, is the one that we consume by the clients,
因此，第一个是区块链测试，是客户消费的测试，
the high format and status formats. Let's just open one of them just to see how they look like.
高格式和状态格式。让我们打开其中一个只是为了看看它们的外观。
There you go.
你去。
So, yeah, everything is here.
所以，是的，一切都在这里。
This is the JSON output.
这是JSON输出。
And really nicely here, we have the name of the test, exactly what we executed.
在这里真的很好，我们有测试的名称，正是我们执行的。
And this is state test.
这是国家测试。
It means that we only have one transaction in this test.
这意味着我们在此测试中只有一项交易。
And you can see it down here.
您可以在这里看到它。
We have the transaction here.
我们在这里有交易。
You have all the properties of the transaction.
您拥有交易的所有属性。
you also have the pre-state and the environment.
您还拥有预状态和环境。
So in this case, you can see that environment contains
因此，在这种情况下，您可以看到环境包含
simple information that comprises the block,
包括块的简单信息，
what the environment will be, namely the block.
环境将是什么，即区块。
And you can see the number, time step, and all that stuff,
您可以看到数字，时间步骤以及所有这些内容，
and the base fee.
和基本费用。
And you can also see, more importantly,
您还可以看到，更重要的是
do you guys remember the address where we save our code to?
你们还记得我们将代码保存到的地址吗？
This is right here.
就在这里。
So we have address number 100.
因此，我们有100号地址。
it. And we have the code here, which is what we generated using this fancy code over here.
它。我们在这里有代码，这是我们在此处使用此奇特代码生成的代码。
And this is what gets executed because the two destinations, all the transactions,
这就是执行的原因，因为两个目的地，所有交易，
is this exact same address. Then the transaction goes to here, executes all this, and then we
这是完全相同的地址。然后交易转到这里，执行所有这些，然后我们
verify the post, which is also in this file. And you can see, one important thing is that
验证该文件中也是该帖子。您可以看到，重要的一件事是
in the state test format, we don't verify exactly, specifically every single key of the storage,
在状态测试格式中，我们没有准确验证，特别是存储的每个键，
but we verify the hash, the state root. This is what gives us the pass or fail of a transaction
但是我们验证了哈希，状态根。这就是使我们通过交易的通行证或失败的原因
test, or the state test, sorry, when it's consumed by the execution client. And this is just for one
测试或状态测试，对不起，当执行客户端消耗时。这只是一个
test but you can see that we have many tests here in this same file which is
测试，但您可以看到我们在同一文件中有许多测试
dub1, dub2, dub3 and so on so forth so on total should be like 16 tests I
dub1，dub2，dub3等等，因此总计应该像16次测试i
think yeah there you go so yeah that's basically the gist of how this
是的，你去了，是的，这基本上就是这样的要点
framework works I encourage everyone to just go and take a look and it's really
框架工作，我鼓励每个人都去看看，这确实是
fun to write this test it's it's in Python if you know Python before you can
写这项测试很有趣，如果您知道python，那就在Python
use this it's very straightforward and yeah let me go back to the presentation
使用这个非常简单，是的，让我回到演示文稿
yeah all right so we have um two other tools very important tools this is the fussy uh evm um
是的，好吧，我们还有其他两个工具非常重要的工具，这是挑剔的UH EVM UM
currently on the execution specters we don't generate first a test this is done by distal
当前在执行幽灵上，我们不是首先生成测试，这是由远端完成的
which is written by Marius from the Go team.
这是由GO团队的Marius撰写的。
He wrote this tool.
他写了这个工具。
It's a companionship to this other tool,
这是另一个工具的陪伴，
which generates FOSS code.
生成FOSS代码。
Then you use Go EVM Lab,
然后，您使用GO EVM实验室，
which is a tool that you use to one input,
这是您用于一个输入的工具，
and then you run this input
然后您运行此输入
with many of the different clients.
与许多不同的客户。
Then you check for differences.
然后，您检查差异。
It's spawned a lot of bugs,
它产生了很多错误，
and it's really useful
这真的很有用
because when you're writing functional testing,
因为当您编写功能测试时，
it's really hard to really come up with every single edge case that you can think of.
真的很难想到您可以想到的每种边缘情况。
So this tool is a very good companionship to what we write using the execution spec tests.
因此，此工具是我们使用执行规格测试编写的非常好的陪伴。
And also another important part is the execution AP testing.
另一个重要的部分是执行AP测试。
This is done inside of this repository.
这是在此存储库中完成的。
Let me just show you quickly.
让我快速告诉你。
Basically, all the execution APIs that you use to query the execution client,
基本上，您用于查询执行客户端的所有执行API，
for example, get a block, get a transaction, send a transaction,
例如，获取一个块，获取交易，发送交易，
all that stuff, it's listed in this repository.
所有这些内容，都在此存储库中列出。
Let me show you real quick how does that look.
让我快速告诉您它的外观。
So we have this repository, and then you have tests.
因此，我们有这个存储库，然后您进行了测试。
And then you can see that you have one or two tests per each RPC directive.
然后，您可以看到每个RPC指令都有一两个测试。
directive so for example it underscore call then you can go and see here and
指令因此，例如它强调了调用，然后您可以去这里查看和
every single one of this it's like an input and then expected up it's very
每一个都像一个输入，然后期望这是非常
simple all of them have like this prerequisite which is this the chain
简单所有的人都有这样的先决条件，这就是链
because you have to have a chain a preset chain if you are expecting a fixed
因为如果您期望固定
outcome you have to have a Genesis chain and all that and so forth
结果您必须拥有一个创世纪链等等
There you go.
你去。
Consensus layer testing.
共识层测试。
This is all done in the consensus spec repository.
这一切都是在共识规范存储库中完成的。
And it's for testing specifically it's a very similar idea to what execution spec test does,
这是针对测试的，这与执行规范测试的想法非常相似，
which is that you have the output it's a fixture which the clients can consume.
这是您的输出是客户可以消费的固定装置。
One of the main differences is that since you have the actual specification contained
主要区别之一是，由于您包含实际规范
in the same repository, you don't have any dependencies.
在同一存储库中，您没有任何依赖关系。
You don't depend on any consensus layer client.
您不依赖任何共识层客户端。
So this is very helpful because you have the test, you have the specification, you have
因此，这是非常有帮助的，因为您有测试，有规格，
everything in the same repository.
在同一存储库中的所有内容。
It's very, very fancy.
这非常非常花哨。
Let me show you just this part.
让我向您展示这部分。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
And if you go into the consensus specs, you go into the tests,
如果您进入共识规范，则进入测试，
you can go in here and see all the formats that can be output
您可以进入这里，查看所有可以输出的格式
from this repository.
来自此存储库。
These are very many different formats that test different things
这些是测试不同事物的许多不同格式
of the consensus layer.
共识层。
it's a great deal more than we generate for the execution specs we only generate blockchain test
这比我们仅生成区块链测试的执行规范生成的要多得多
format and status which is expected to change we are going to introduce more more formats as
格式和状态有望改变我们将引入更多格式
necessary but yeah you can see the great deal of formats that you can generate using this test is
是的，是的，您可以看到使用此测试可以生成的大量格式是
very useful because you can very granularly test every single every single small layer it's
非常有用，因为您可以非常细粒度测试它的每一层
basically like unit testing every single aspect of the of the consensus layer and it's very efficient
基本上就像单位测试共识层的每个方面，这是非常有效的
also. I recommend coming into here, into this repository, and giving this
还。我建议进入这里，进入这个存储库，并给予此
read, because it's it's not as straightforward maybe, but it's very
阅读，因为这也许不是那么简单，但是
rewarding to understand how this test are filled.
理解如何填充该测试。
So, going into the last part of the later part of the
因此，进入后期的最后一部分
presentation um we do testing of the execution layer and consensus layers separately but we also
演示文稿，我们分别对执行层和共识层进行测试，但我们也
do some testing that is cross cross layer testing which is very important to know that everything
进行一些测试，即横层测试，这一点非常重要的是要知道一切
fits together it's called end-to-end testing it's basically just building chains from from genesis
适合它称为端到端测试，它基本上只是从创世纪建立链条
to some point and then verifying that everything all the interactions happened correctly between
到某个时候，然后验证所有互动的一切都正确地发生在
the execution and consensus clients. We have different test for this, test tweets for this.
执行和共识客户。我们对此有不同的测试，对此进行测试推文。
I'm gonna just mention just a few of them, because otherwise it will be a very, very long
我只会提及其中的一些，因为否则它将是一个非常非常长的
presentation. So we have Hive, which is the main tool that I personally focus on and the
推介会。因此，我们有Hive，这是我个人关注的主要工具，
room testing team focuses on, but we also have more tools that were developed by the
房间测试团队的重点是
DevOps team and also in conjunction with other companies. So we have the Assertor,
DevOps团队，并与其他公司结合。所以我们有主张，
which is basically just a tool that we can use to give it an input and then expect some expected
基本上，这只是我们可以用来给它输入的工具，然后期望一些预期的
output and assert that the output was correct in any of the chains. Have it being Hive chain,
输出并断言在任何链中的输出都是正确的。它是蜂巢链，
a DevNet, a TestNet, or even MainNet. It's relevant, you can do it all with the
DEVNET，测试网，甚至是主网。这很重要，您可以用
The assertor is very nice tool.
断言是非常好的工具。
We also have the Kurtosis package,
我们还有峰度包，
which was developed by the Kurtosis team.
是由峰度小组开发的。
It's a very, very nice tool,
这是一个非常非常好的工具，
which allows to do simple stuff
允许做简单的事情
from just spawning your own local Ethereum chain,
从只产生自己的当地以太链链，
which is comprised by the execution client
由执行客户端组成
and the consensus client,
和共识客户，
or go all the way up to even launching ShadowForks,
或直到启动Shadowforks，
which is something I will explain in a little bit.
我将在一点点解释这一点。
It's a very, very nice package.
这是一个非常非常好的包装。
and it's um i recommend it if you want to run something quick this is this is one of the tools
如果您想快速运行一些东西，这就是工具之一，我建议这样做
to go to um yeah i'm gonna go a little bit more into hive because this is uh one of also tools
要去嗯，是的，我要去更多的蜂巢，因为这是一种工具之一
that i work with so um yeah basically hive is a framework that gives you gives you the tester
我与之合作的um是的，基本上是蜂巢是一个为您提供测试人员的框架
a way of spawning tests
产卵测试的一种方式
and spawning clients inside of tests,
并在测试中产生客户，
namely execution clients and consensus clients.
即执行客户和共识客户。
So you can create tests that you start your tests
因此您可以创建测试的测试
and you have something very specific in mind.
而且您有一些非常具体的事情。
For example, you want to test the deposits
例如，您想测试存款
in the consensus data chain.
在共识数据链中。
So then you start your test
因此，您开始考试
and then you start a execution client.
然后您启动一个执行客户端。
I'm sorry, you start first the consensus client,
对不起，您首先开始共识客户端，
then you start the execution client
然后您启动执行客户端
you put them together
你把它们放在一起
you launch some deposits
您发起了一些存款
into the consensus client
进入共识客户
and then you expect something
然后您期待一些东西
and at the end of the test
在测试结束时
if everything went correctly
如果一切都正确
you instruct that test is correctly finished
您指示测试正确完成
and passed
并通过
and then you wrap up
然后你总结
it's a very nice framework
这是一个非常好的框架
for doing very
做非常
very functional and specific testing
非常功能和特定的测试
you have to have in mind
你必须牢记
exactly what you want to test
正是您要测试的
when you roll and write simulators.
当您滚动并编写模拟器时。
The way it works is that,
它的工作方式是，
let me see if I have a slide, yes.
让我看看我是否有幻灯片，是的。
The way it works is we have the Hive server,
它的工作方式是我们拥有Hive Server，
which is the main orchestrator
这是主要的编排
of everything that we run in this,
在我们在此过程中运行的一切
but you also have simulators.
但是您也有模拟器。
The simulator's job is to know what to do
模拟器的工作是知道该怎么办
in terms of when to start a test,
关于何时开始测试的
when to end it, when to start a client,
何时结束它，何时启动客户端，
when to end the client, and so on and so forth.
何时结束客户，等等。
So the first step is that you build the Hive server,
因此，第一步是您构建Hive Server，
and I'll show it in a little bit.
我会稍微展示。
I have a demo for this.
我有一个演示。
It's really, really quick.
真的很快。
And you start your Hive server,
然后您启动蜂巢服务器，
and you tell your Hive server to start a given simulator,
然后您告诉蜂巢服务器启动给定的模拟器，
and it will go on and start a Docker container
它将继续并启动一个Docker容器
with the simulator.
使用模拟器。
And basically, the simulator is just another program
基本上，模拟器只是另一个程序
that contains all the instructions
其中包含所有说明
on how to run this test.
关于如何运行此测试。
So the simulator starts,
因此，模拟器开始，
the simulator knows that it's being run by Hive, then it goes on and does its thing,
模拟器知道它是由Hive运行的，然后继续进行并做事，
it starts a test, it starts a client, and then performs some calculations and things,
它开始测试，启动客户端，然后执行一些计算和事物，
and then it ends the client, or ends the test, or aborts the test, or fails, or passes the test,
然后它结束客户端，或结束测试，或中止测试，或失败或通过测试，
and then that's basically it. A single simulator can start many tests at once,
然后基本上就是这样。一个模拟器可以一次启动许多测试，
in parallel, it can start many clients in parallel also,
同时，它也可以同时启动许多客户，
and it can orchestrate many different scenarios
它可以协调许多不同的情况
for the execution and consensus clients to execute.
为了执行和共识客户端执行。
The nice thing is that you don't have to worry
好事是您不必担心
in your simulator on how you start up.
在模拟器中有关您的启动方式。
For example, let's say, okay,
例如，假设，好的，
I want to start a execution client,
我想启动一个执行客户端，
but I don't know how to start it
但是我不知道该如何开始
because Go Ethereum and Nethermine
因为去以太坊和nethermine
are started in different ways.
以不同的方式开始。
for example, we have Docker images for each,
例如，我们每个都有docker图像，
but even so you have like parameters,
但是即使如此，您也有喜欢参数，
for example, go theorem has a different parameter
例如，GO定理具有不同的参数
for how to specify the Genesis file or whatever,
有关如何指定创世纪文件或其他任何内容，
as compared to Nethermine.
与Nethermine相比。
So one of the goals of the Hive server
因此，蜂巢服务器的目标之一
is to abstract all this.
是为了抽象所有这些。
So you start your simulator, Hive tells you,
因此，您启动模拟器，Hive告诉您，
okay, you have go theorem, Nethermine,
好吧，你有定理，nethermine，
PZU and whatever, and the simulator
Pzu和其他，以及模拟器
goes into and says, okay, let's start the go with it.
进入说，好吧，让我们开始使用它。
And then it starts go with theorem
然后开始使用定理
with all the parameters already set for you.
所有参数已经为您设置了。
And then you can just focus on testing
然后您可以专注于测试
for that specific execution client.
对于该特定的执行客户端。
And the Hive server will start the execution
蜂巢服务器将启动执行
or consensus clients for you.
或为您提供共识客户。
But the nice thing is that from the simulation,
但是好事是从模拟中，
you can communicate to both the Hive server
您可以与两个Hive Server通信
to start more clients,
为了启动更多客户，
or you can communicate to the execution client
或者您可以与执行客户端进行通信
or the consensus client directly.
或直接共识客户端。
So it's a very nice way
所以这是一个非常好的方法
of just abstracting
只是抽象
a lot of stuff away from you.
您有很多东西。
The test writer
测试作者
to only focus on
只专注于
testing actual things
测试实际的事情
in the image of the clients.
在客户的形象中。
We have many simulators
我们有很多模拟器
for Hive.
对于蜂巢。
They are all in Golang
他们都在戈兰
and they are all contained
它们都包含
in the Hive repository,
在蜂巢存储库中
but it's possible
但这是可能的
to write any simulator in any language that you need.
用所需的任何语言编写任何模拟器。
This is for, we have also a library for Python,
这是为了，我们还有一个python的图书馆，
which is not out yet,
尚未出来，
and still has some work to do,
而且还有一些工作要做，
some work left to do on it.
还有一些工作要做。
But yeah, for the time being, it's only on Golang.
但是，是的，就目前而言，只有在Golang上。
And as you can see, here are all the simulators
如您所见，这是所有模拟器
that at least on master high branch
至少在高级分支机构上
that are contained into Hive.
被包含在蜂巢中。
And we have different things.
我们有不同的东西。
Like, for example, we have the peer-to-peer,
例如，我们有点对点，
which is like the way of communicating execution clients in between them.
就像在他们之间传达执行客户端的方式一样。
So this simulator pertains to testing this part of the communication.
因此，该模拟器与测试通信的这一部分有关。
Just start clients, communicate them with each other,
只需启动客户，彼此交流，
and verify that this communication took place
并验证这种沟通发生了
and it was correct and successful.
这是正确和成功的。
And we also have the Ethereum normal,
我们也有以太坊的正常
which contains many different things,
其中包含许多不同的东西，
namely the RPC
即RPC
the RPC compact is
RPC紧凑型是
if you guys remember
如果你还记得
this other page
另一页
that we saw which is the execution
我们看到了执行
app is, this thing here
应用是，这东西在这里
it goes into that repository
它进入该存储库
and collects every single one of
并收集每个
these files
这些文件
and then executes them over RPC
然后通过RPC执行它们
on the running clients
在运行的客户端
using the method that we just
使用我们仅的方法
saw, so it's really important
看到，所以这很重要
for the consumption
用于消费
of this
这
of these tests to use Hive only for the RPC combat.
在这些测试中，仅用于RPC战斗。
But we also have more things.
但是我们还有更多的东西。
For example, we have the consensus.
例如，我们有共识。
This loads test for Ethereum tests
这将负载以太坊测试的测试
and just passes them into the client, verifies them.
然后将它们传递到客户中，验证它们。
We also have the Engine API.
我们也有引擎API。
This is very important because it tests
这很重要，因为它测试
the communication from the consensus client
共识客户的沟通
into the execution client via the Engine API,
通过引擎API进入执行客户端，
which is defined over here in the execution APIs.
在执行API中在此处定义。
The important part of this simulator
该模拟器的重要部分
is that it does not use a consensus client.
是它不使用共识客户端。
And the reason is that it wants to test
原因是它要测试
some very specific sequence of engine API commands
一些非常具体的引擎API命令序列
and some very specific Genesis properties.
以及一些非常具体的创世纪特性。
So the way that we do that
所以我们这样做的方式
and without the interruption of the consensus client,
没有共识客户的中断，
it's by generating a mock consensus client,
是通过生成模拟共识客户端，
which is basically just does the engine API calls
基本上只是引擎API调用
that we exactly require.
我们完全需要。
We also have the GraphQL, which is test the GraphQL.
我们还有GraphQl，它是测试GraphQl。
The PySpec is the basically execution specters.
PYSPEC基本上是执行幽灵。
They are all consumed over here and some sync test also.
它们都在这里被消耗掉了，还进行了一些同步测试。
And, but also very important is the f2.
而且，但也非常重要的是F2。
This is a legacy name, don't mind it.
这是一个旧的名字，不要介意。
This contains all the interrupt testing between the consensus layer and the execution layer.
这包含共识层和执行层之间的所有中断测试。
So this actually, this one, this simulators over here, do actually spawn a consensus client and an execution client at the same time.
因此，实际上，这个模拟器在此处确实会同时产生共识客户端和执行客户端。
And it's purpose is just to test some specific scenarios that are happening, for example, in the goon,
它的目的只是测试一些正在发生的特定情况，例如在傻瓜中，
you have blobs, blobs sending blobs,
您有斑点，斑点发送斑点，
and doing the blob stuff,
并做斑点的事情，
and verifying that the consensus client
并验证共识客户
and the execution client behave the way expected
执行客户的行为以预期的方式行事
when these blobs are fed into them.
当这些斑点被送入其中时。
And it's very nice because it orchestrates both things,
它非常好，因为它策划了这两种事情，
both the execution client and the consensus client
执行客户端和共识客户端
at the same time.
同时。
And it's really nice to see how it works.
看到它是如何工作的，真是太好了。
Let me see.
让我看看。
What else?
还有什么？
A small component portal,
一个小的组件门户，
more simulators, different implementations.
更多的模拟器，不同的实现。
This is a different implementation it uses different ethereum clients, but it's the same idea
这是一种不同的实现，它使用了不同的以太坊客户端，但这是同一想法
Yeah
是的
Yeah, okay, so let me just quickly just I just want to show a little bit of how it runs it's really
是的，好吧，所以让我迅速让我只是想展示它的运行方式
Really simple
真的很简单
One of the important parts is that you first have to clone the repository as always
重要部分之一是您首先必须一如既往地克隆存储库
Just go over here into hive it in hive
只需在这里进入蜂巢中的蜂巢
git clone, you clone it into your local host, and then assuming that you have golan installed,
git克隆，将其克隆到本地主机中，然后假设您已经安装了Golan，
you can just go build it, and you will be building hive, which is this executable right here.
您可以去构建它，然后您将建造Hive，这是在这里可执行的。
That right there. So this executable pertains to this server over here, the server that orchestrates
那在那里。因此，此可执行文件与此服务器有关
everything it's basically a very fancy docker container instantiator and
一切基本上都是一个非常精美的码头容器实例化器，
orchestrator that's it's role and so let's let's run a simple test I think I
乐队的角色是角色，所以让我们来进行一个简单的测试，我想我
have something in the area yeah okay let's let's run a simple test that is
在该地区有一些东西，是的，让我们进行一个简单的测试
just the testnet test for an execution client and a consensus client let me just
只是执行客户端和共识客户端的TestNet测试，让我
I hope it's not that bad okay so we're gonna use the hive command yes
我希望还不错，所以我们要使用hive命令是
we're gonna use the hive command and we're gonna instruct it to use three
我们要使用蜂巢命令，我们将指示它使用三个
different clients so the first client is the Netdermind client which is the
不同的客户端，因此第一个客户端是NetDerMind客户端
execution client that we want to use.
我们要使用的执行客户端。
And the second, third clients are both part
第二，第三个客户都是
of the consensus layer,
共识层的
but they have two different responsibilities.
但是他们有两个不同的责任。
Hive requires a beacon node and a validator client
Hive需要一个信标节点和验证器客户端
to be run for the consensus layer part.
要为共识层部分运行。
So that's where we are specifying here,
这就是我们在这里指定的地方，
it's Prism in this case,
在这种情况下是棱镜，
and we're using beacon node,
我们正在使用信标节点，
just the beacon node part of Prism,
只是棱镜的标准节点部分，
and then validator client,
然后验证器客户端，
the validator client part of Prism.
验证者客户的一部分。
Then we're going to specify a simulator,
然后，我们将指定一个模拟器，
which is this flag over here.
这是这里的标志。
And then we are going to use it to Tenkun,
然后我们将它将其用于Tenkun，
which is the latest simulator that we have.
这是我们拥有的最新模拟器。
And we're going to limit this to just a single,
我们将仅限于一个
let me see, test, no, me.
让我看看，测试，不，我。
Okay, if you want to know the names of the actual tests
好吧，如果您想知道实际测试的名称
tests that we're running, you can go into the simulator and just get, for example, let's go to
我们正在运行的测试，您可以进入模拟器，例如，让我们开始
add2 and let's go to dencun and let's look up the suites. You can actually look it here it's the it
add2，让我们去Dencun，让我们看看套房。您实际上可以在这里看它
will list all of the all of the all of the tests that are currently running on this on this
将列出当前在此上进行的所有所有测试
simulator and let's go to the easiest one which is the dencun testnet.
模拟器，让我们去找最简单的dencun testnet。
it. And you can see that every single test case in here will have a specific common line that you
它。您会看到，这里的每个测试用例都会有您的特定共同行
can just copy paste. And let me just do that. This dash is not important. This can be removed.
可以复制糊。让我这样做。这个破折号并不重要。这可以删除。
And let's just copy paste it here. And let's just hit enter to see what happens. The first thing
让我们在这里复制粘贴。让我们点击Enter以查看会发生什么。第一件事
that happens is that, okay, a hive starts and it builds something that is called high proxy.
这样做的是，好的，一个蜂巢开始，它构建了一种称为高代理的东西。
This is not important it's basically just like an intermediary between the execution clients and the consensus clients and the hive server.
这并不重要，基本上就像执行客户端与共识客户端和Hive服务器之间的中介一样。
The second thing that it's building over here, it's, I cannot pause it, well, the second thing it's building is the execution client.
它在这里建造的第二件事是，我无法暂停它，好吧，第二件事是构建的是执行客户端。
You can see that Nethermind is being built here and it built correctly.
您可以看到在这里建造了Nethermind，并且可以正确构建。
and it's important to build clients
建立客户很重要
because you can know that building
因为你知道那座建筑物
will give you the latest version
会给你最新版本
that we are trying to test.
我们正在尝试测试。
So in this case,
因此，在这种情况下，
we are pulling, nevermind the latest master.
我们正在拉动最新的大师。
So also it might contain bugs
因此，它也可能包含错误
because this is not a release,
因为这不是发布
this is master.
这是主人。
So there are things,
所以有东西，
obviously in the master branch of each client
显然在每个客户的主分支
that can contain bugs,
可以包含错误，
but this is the purpose of Hive
但这是蜂巢的目的
to catch those errors.
捕获这些错误。
So the important thing here is use the latest master.
因此，这里重要的是使用最新的主人。
The next things that are building is the same thing
构建的下一件事情是同一件事
for the consensus client, consensus layer, sorry.
对于共识客户，共识层，对不起。
We are using Prism, the Bitcoin node,
我们正在使用Prism，Bitcoin节点，
the Prism, the belated claim, same thing.
棱镜，迟来的主张，同样的事情。
We're using the latest master, which is not a release,
我们正在使用最新的主人，这不是版本，
it's something newer, it's basically just a beta version.
这是更新的东西，基本上只是一个beta版本。
So there could be bugs in this.
因此，这可能会有错误。
And lastly, we're gonna build the simulator.
最后，我们将构建模拟器。
So the simulator in here is the one that we specified,
因此，此处的模拟器是我们指定的模拟器，
but this flag here that we use, which is the limit,
但是这里使用的这个标志，这是极限，
it's a flag that is going into the simulator.
这是进入模拟器的标志。
So we're passing the flag into simulator to tell it to,
因此，我们将标志传递到模拟器中以告诉它，
please do not run anything else but this specific test.
请不要进行其他任何特定测试。
So it's not gonna run the entire simulator
所以它不会运行整个模拟器
and the direct capability of testing of that simulator
以及该模拟器测试的直接能力
it's just gonna run this one single test.
它只是将进行一次一次测试。
And now it's running,
现在它正在运行，
and you can see that it started several things
而且您可以看到它开始了几件事
and it's currently running
目前正在运行
because it's doing it's thing in the background.
因为它是在后台做的。
But what we can see it right now it's very silly
但是我们现在可以看到的，这很愚蠢
is that we have all of these things running in Docker.
是我们所有这些东西都在Docker中运行。
So you can see that we have spawned
因此您可以看到我们已经产生了
two different execution clients
两个不同的执行客户端
and two different Validator and Baconaut clients
以及两个不同的验证者和Baconaut客户
for the Conscious Layer.
对于意识层。
This, the reason is that since this is a full test net
这是因为这是一个完整的测试网
that we are using,
我们正在使用的
and normally the consensus clients require
通常，共识客户需要
at least one peer to know that everything is same, right?
至少一个同伴知道一切都一样，对吗？
Because otherwise,
因为否则，
if you don't have any single peer to connect to,
如果您没有任何单个对等点可以连接到
that means something wrong is happening.
这意味着正在发生错误的事情。
So in this case, we instantiate two pairs of everything
因此，在这种情况下，我们实例化了两双所有内容
and let the simulator do it's thing.
并让模拟器做这件事。
And then we can actually go into the file.
然后我们实际上可以进入文件。
There's a simulator log file that we can use just to see.
我们可以使用一个模拟器日志文件来查看。
The main output of this is the locks
其中的主要输出是锁
in the workspace.
在工作区。
So in your local host, in the High folder that you have,
因此，在您的本地主机中，在您拥有的高文件夹中
when you run your workspace,
当您运行工作区时，
you will see this locks directory.
您将看到此锁目录。
And if you go in here,
如果你去这里，
you will see the output of the actual simulator.
您将看到实际模拟器的输出。
So you will see everything that is happening
因此，您将看到正在发生的一切
in the simulator, what it's running, what it's doing,
在模拟器中，它正在运行什么，正在做什么，
what it's requesting, everything you will see it here.
它要求什么，您将在这里看到的所有内容。
This is just a Genesis file,
这只是一个创世纪文件，
but then you can see here that the chain is progressing.
但是然后您可以在这里看到链条正在发展。
So you can see that the simulator,
因此，您可以看到模拟器，
one of the jobs that it does is just to keep track
它所做的工作之一就是保持跟踪
of everything that is happening.
正在发生的一切。
So the first thing that it keeps track
因此，它保持跟踪的第一件事
is that the chain is actually progressing.
是链实际上正在发展。
So you can see that we are jumping
因此您可以看到我们正在跳跃
from one slot to the next one.
从一个插槽到下一个插槽。
So four, five, the chain is changing,
因此，四个，五个链条正在变化，
The head chain is changing.
头链正在改变。
It means that blocks are being produced.
这意味着正在生产块。
And in the meantime,
同时，
also there's a lot of testing in the background,
也在背景中进行了很多测试，
which is sending block transactions,
这是发送块交易，
verifying those block transactions that go inside
验证那些进入内部的块交易
and everything's fine.
一切都很好。
This is, I think it's a lengthy task
这是，我认为这是一项漫长的任务
because it's to wait for finalization.
因为要等待最终确定。
So we're gonna wrap it there for the demo.
因此，我们将其包裹在那里进行演示。
Otherwise it's gonna take too long.
否则将花费太长时间。
But yeah, that's basically it just for,
但是，是的，基本上就是这样，
Let me just cancel this.
让我取消这个。
And I think there's only five minutes left.
我认为还剩五分钟。
And so are there any questions yet
还有什么问题
or should I just keep going?
还是我应该继续前进？
Yeah, let's take a second for questions, I guess,
是的，让我们稍等一下，我想
because it's been a lot, Mario.
因为很多，马里奥。
Thank you so much, by the way, it's amazing.
非常感谢您，顺便说一句，这太神奇了。
I love the live session and everything, really great.
我喜欢现场会议和一切，真的很棒。
Yeah, back to that, actually,
是的，回到那，实际上，
there was one interesting question I wanted to ask
我想问一个有趣的问题
because the execution spec tests have it as dependency,
因为执行规范测试将其作为依赖项，所以
the get execution environment.
获得执行环境。
So the question is like,
所以问题就像，
and you touched on it a little bit,
你稍微谈到了一点
but maybe if you can elaborate,
但是也许如果你能详细说明，
so like how, like we,
所以像我们一样
I guess we don't assume that there is no bug in get,
我想我们不认为Get中没有错误，
so like how do you identify
所以就像你如何识别
if there is actually bug in the dependency
如果依赖关系实际上存在错误
and yeah, how do we work with that?
是的，我们如何处理？
So yeah, ideally, the ideal situation
是的，理想情况下，理想的情况
is that we don't depend on get, that's the truth.
是我们不依靠获得，这就是事实。
So for as a workaround with that, we are working for to have a another execution client, which is just specs oriented, which is called ELSE it's execution specs repo.
因此，作为解决方法，我们正在努力拥有另一个执行客户端，该客户端只是面向规格，这被称为“ else execution Specs repo”。
Ideally, we should not use get, but now as of now, we do depend on get and that the reason and the reason why it's not it's not it's it's not a big deal is because we generally we also verify the results of the post date.
理想情况下，我们不应该使用GET，但是现在到目前为止，我们确实取决于GET，原因和原因不是不是这并不是什么大不了的，因为我们通常还验证了发布日期的结果。
it so we have to be very careful when we write a test that we actually verify everything that
因此，当我们编写测试时，我们必须非常小心
we expect the only thing that we don't go into detail is the gas consumption because it's really
我们期望我们唯一不详细介绍的是汽油消耗，因为它确实是
tricky to get it right in testing and it can get um to false positives and it can get a lot of noise
棘手的测试中，它可以使UM呈误报，并且会产生很多噪音
but other things which is the keys of the storage the values all of that we actually
但是其他东西是存储的钥匙，我们实际上所有的值
verify them when we get the response from geth so there's no much leeway for for box
当我们从Geth得到回应时，请验证它们，所以Box没有太多余地
affecting us in get.
影响我们。
From time to time, we do find bugs in get
我们不时发现错误
when we are filling tests, and then we go report it.
当我们填写测试时，然后进行报告。
We have to wait until the get theme fixes those
我们必须等到GET主题修复这些
for us to be able to generate the tests.
让我们能够生成测试。
And in some other rare occasions,
在其他极少数情况下，
we have generated the full test.
我们已经生成了完整的测试。
We have the fixture,
我们有固定装置，
and then we go and run it on other clients,
然后我们去其他客户运行，
and then we get an error.
然后我们有一个错误。
and then sometimes it's most of the times it's an error with the other client but sometimes
然后有时候大多数情况下，这是另一个客户的错误，但有时
it has happened in the past that we found a bug in geth that the other client found so it's yeah
过去，我们在Geth发现了另一个客户发现的错误，所以是的
it's it's it's a stepped process as as of now it will get better in the future but as of now
到目前为止，这是一个逐步的过程，它将在将来变得更好，但是到目前为止
there are some places that it's it's we have to be very careful where where we where what we what
在某些地方，我们必须非常小心我们在哪里。
verify what we let pass. For example, the gas limits is very tricky, as I said,
验证我们让我们通过的东西。例如，正如我说的那样，气体极限非常棘手
that's something that we let the other clients verify for us. But yeah.
这是我们让其他客户为我们验证的东西。但是，是的。
Awesome, thanks for explaining that. Another question is more advice for an EIP author,
太棒了，感谢您的解释。另一个问题是对EIP作者的更多建议，
for example, who implements some change to RPC method, which doesn't need to change the state
例如，谁对RPC方法进行了一些更改，而RPC方法不需要更改状态
transition or anything, just for example add some extra data in RPC response,
过渡或任何事物，例如在RPC响应中添加一些额外数据，
what would be a way to test this, to compare the outputs of different implementations,
是什么方法来比较不同实现的输出，
for example, what is something that it doesn't have much overhead?
例如，它没有太多的开销？
So if I understood correctly,
因此，如果我正确理解，
so the RPC is something that you can test without going into writing the test that
因此，RPC是您可以测试的东西而无需编写测试
that we just described.
我们刚刚描述的。
So for that scenario,
因此，对于这种情况，
you will go into the execution APIs repository,
您将进入执行API库，
which is the part that I just glanced upon a little bit,
这是我刚刚瞥了一眼的一部分，
which is where the RPC tests live.
这是RPC测试的所在地。
Those RPC tests,
那些RPC测试，
they are very, very self-contained,
他们非常非常独立，
very small and easy to write.
很小且易于编写。
For those specific kind of VAPs,
对于那些特定类型的VAP，
I would suggest going onto the execution APIs repository
我建议进入执行APIS存储库
just giving it a look, giving it a look at the tests, what we test here.
只要让它看一下，让它看一下测试，我们在这里测试的内容。
So if you have something to introduce to the RPC of the Ethereum clients,
因此，如果您有一些内容可以介绍以太坊客户的RPC，
this is the place to start, I think, the execution APIs repository.
我认为这是执行API存储库的起点。
Okay, awesome. Thank you so much.
好吧，很棒。太感谢了。
Yeah, one question, going back to your example there, the demo that you did,
是的，一个问题，回到您的榜样，您做过的演示，
it was the tests for the opcodes, which was 48 test cases,
这是对opcodes的测试，即48个测试用例，
which is like three per opcode.
就像每个OpCode三个。
So what were the cases where we had 48 test cases there?
那么我们那里有48例测试用例的情况是什么？
Definitely.
确实。
So we had 16 opcodes,
所以我们有16个opcodes，
but for each one of those,
但是对于每个中的每一个
we generated the three test formats.
我们生成了三种测试格式。
So the state test format,
因此，状态测试格式，
the blockchain test format,
区块链测试格式，
and the blockchain test hive format.
和区块链测试蜂巢格式。
So every single one of the formats has its own purpose.
因此，每种格式都有自己的目的。
State test is very self-contained,
国家测试非常独立，
just one transaction in the pre-state,
在预状态中只有一笔交易，
out the state root, check, that's it.
淘汰状态根，检查就是这样。
The blockchain test, which is
区块链测试，
what the clients consume, they can consume it,
客户消费的东西，他们可以消费，
just check the block header, everything
只需检查块标头，一切
passes. And lastly, the hype test,
通过。最后，炒作测试，
which contains everything, like everything
其中包含一切，就像一切一样
that comes as if it was coming
好像来了
from the consensus layer. So that's
从共识层。就是这样
why we have three different test formats
为什么我们有三种不同的测试格式
to consume and to generate.
消费和生成。
I get it.
我得到它。
All the formats are pretty cool.
所有格式都很酷。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Yeah.
是的。
Yeah, one more question, maybe we can combine these.
是的，还有一个问题，也许我们可以将它们结合在一起。
What do you find the most complex to test in EL or CL?
您发现在EL或CL中测试的最复杂的是什么？
What is the most heavy?
最重的是什么？
And how much time it actually takes to run all these tests,
以及运行所有这些测试实际需要多少时间
like, for example, to test the counter work?
例如，测试计数器工作吗？
I would say it really depends.
我会说这确实取决于。
So for the first question, what's the most complex?
因此，对于第一个问题，最复杂的是什么？
I think the interoperability is something that is not pretty much solved yet.
我认为互操作性尚未解决。
it. And this is the most complex part, in my opinion. The, the EVM part is also complex,
它。在我看来，这是最复杂的部分。 EVM部分也很复杂，
but it in its own way, there are a lot of nuances that you have to be aware, when you're
但是它以其自己的方式，当您有很多细微差别时，
writing an EVM test, it always happens that, oh, I forgot about this thing of the idea
编写EVM测试，总是会发生，哦，我忘记了这个想法
that this side effect in devian somewhere else, and it affected my test. So it's you
这种副作用在其他地方的副作用，并影响了我的测试。所以是你
really have to, well, you kind of know everything of the EM, but it's like a back and forth
真的，您必须知道EM的所有内容，但这就像一个来回
and go and check and specifications,
然后去检查和规格，
the yellow paper and everything.
黄纸和一切。
So it's a very, very long process.
因此，这是一个非常非常漫长的过程。
It's like it's it's it's really nice because it's rewarding.
就像它真的很棒，因为它很有意义。
Once you have your EVM test completed and finalized
完成EVM测试后，完成并完成
and it works it's really nice because you know
它起作用真的很好，因为您知道
that everything is correct, but it's complex indeed.
一切都是正确的，但确实很复杂。
It's it's it's time consuming.
这是耗时的。
And the other part, how much does it take?
另一部分，它需要多少？
It takes a lot.
这需要很多。
So depending on the software,
因此，根据软件的不同
the hardware that we are running on,
我们正在运行的硬件，
The problem with the consensus test, the EVM test,
共识测试，EVM测试的问题，
is that every single test instantiates a full client,
是每个测试实例化一个完整的客户端吗？
and then you give it the input, and then you spec the output.
然后将其提供给输入，然后将输出规格。
So it's very time-consuming.
所以这很耗时。
So I think there are up to 10,000 or something tests
所以我认为最多有10,000个或测试
in the Ethereum test repository.
在以太坊测试存储库中。
In the new execution specs, there are only 5,000.
在新的执行规范中，只有5,000个。
So it takes a lot less, and we can parallelize those.
因此，这需要少得多，我们可以并行化。
So I don't have the number, but last time I tested it,
所以我没有这个数字，但是上次我测试了它，
it wasn't so long, maybe five minutes to 10 minutes,
这没有那么长，也许是五分钟到10分钟，
or something for the execution specters in Parallelize
或对执行幽灵的东西并行化
if you have a beefy hardware.
如果您的硬件肥胖。
Otherwise, it's going to take a long time.
否则，这将需要很长时间。
But yeah.
但是，是的。
Okay, thanks so much.
好吧，非常感谢。
That's very interesting.
那很有趣。
Yeah, the next questions are about
是的，下一个问题是关于
how do you communicate bugs to client teams?
您如何将错误传达给客户团队？
I guess it's different from your perspective
我想从你的角度有所不同
as a testing team,
作为一个测试团队，
but also you mentioned that we will get
但您也提到我们会得到
to the bug bounties part,
对于bug赏金部分，
so maybe I'll let you segue into that.
所以也许我会让你陷入困境。
This is very important.
这很重要。
it depends it really depends on the severity of the of the bug if we found found something that
如果我们发现某些东西
affects any live network it's going to be something that is very we have to be very cautious
影响任何实时网络，这将是我们必须非常谨慎的事情
uh normally when when we are developing a new fork for example we were started we were at the
通常，当我们开发新叉时，例如，我们开始
start of cancun um it's it's really easy it's just like submit an issue and something because
坎昆的开始，这真的很容易，就像提交问题和某些东西一样，因为
there's no live network with cancun at that point so it doesn't really matter but the the the closer
那时没有坎昆的现场网络，所以这并不重要，但是近距离
that we get to Cancun being released in any live network,
我们可以在任何现场网络中发布坎昆，
the more cautious that we have to be
我们必须变得越谨慎
when we submit issues.
当我们提交问题时。
It gets to the point where we only communicate this
到了我们只交流这个的地步
to the specific developers
给特定的开发人员
and we get to specific communication
我们进行特定的沟通
and there's special handling
而且有特殊的处理
that you have to take care of
你必须照顾
when we're submitting something
当我们提交一些东西时
that is potentially harmful for a live network.
这可能对现场网络有害。
Yeah.
是的。
Cool, cool, cool.
凉爽，凉爽，凉爽。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
I think we are out of the questions.
我认为我们没有问题。
If there are none, feel free to ask.
如果没有，请随时问。
We are over time.
我们随着时间的流逝。
We should wrap it up.
我们应该把它结合起来。
I actually have a couple more slides.
实际上，我还有更多幻灯片。
I can just fly through them.
我可以飞过它们。
Feel free.
感到自由。
We are all very happy following.
我们都很高兴追随。
Everybody's excited.
每个人都很兴奋。
So feel free to use our time.
因此，请随时使用我们的时间。
Just mind your own time.
请注意自己的时间。
So how much, however, I'm sure you can take it.
但是，我确定您可以接受多少。
No problem.
没问题。
No, let's carry on.
不，让我们继续前进。
I will just fly over the slides.
我将飞过幻灯片。
So yeah, after everything else that I explained before,
是的，在我以前解释过的其他一切之后，
we still have another test methodology to use,
我们还有另一种使用测试方法可以使用
which is the live testnets.
这是实时测试网。
We have the devnets, the ShadowRub forks,
我们有Devnets，Shadowrub叉，
and the public devnets, which all happened
和所有发生的公共Devnets
before the mainnet release.
在主网发布之前。
So for Cancun, mainnet is coming up in three days.
因此，对于坎昆来说，主网将在三天内出现。
So all of this has already passed.
因此，所有这些已经过去了。
And we have many iterations of all of these different testnets.
我们有许多这些不同的测试网络的迭代。
The first one is a devnet.
第一个是Devnet。
It's something that is like, we run a small chain
就像是，我们经营着一条小链
with all the combinations of the clients,
有了客户的所有组合，
but it's a very, very limited size of clients.
但这是一个非常有限的客户。
So we have very few nodes per each chain.
因此，我们每个链节点很少。
And the purpose of this is to test a new proof of concept fork.
这样做的目的是测试新的概念证明。
For example, at the very start of the blobs,
例如，在斑点的一开始，
which it was almost two years ago, I think,
我认为这差不多两年前
devnets is the first way to go.
DEVNets是第一个方法。
You implement the bare minimum,
您实施最低限度，
the function in the proof of concept for each of the clients,
每个客户的概念证明的功能，
and then you launch a devnet with this.
然后，您启动了一个DEVNET。
And then you send things into the chain
然后您将东西发送到链条
and see how it behaves and you verify their behavior.
并查看其行为方式，并验证其行为。
And obviously this is where,
显然，这就是
when the software is not ready for production.
当软件还没有准备好生产时。
So these are very short-lived
所以这些都是非常短暂的
and normally they go down and they go out of sync
通常他们会掉下来，然后退出同步
and a lot of bad things happen,
发生了很多坏事，
but that's what they are for.
但这就是他们的目的。
And another thing that we use is the ShadowForks.
我们使用的另一件事是Shadowforks。
This is a very clever implementation
这是一个非常聪明的实施
that the DevOps team has come up with.
Devops团队提出了。
it's basically you have a clone of Mainnet,
基本上，您有一个Mainnet的克隆，
but on a limited set of nodes,
但是在有限的节点上，
you configure them to activate the upcoming fork early.
您可以配置它们以尽早激活即将到来的叉子。
So for example, in the case of Cancun,
因此，例如，在坎昆的情况下
we sync everything,
我们同步一切，
but this ShadowForks began happening
但是这个阴影开始发生
early last year from June, I think.
我认为去年6月初。
So the clients that we were running
所以我们正在经营的客户
were configured, for example, June 20th of 2023.
被配置为2023年6月20日。
go on with Cancun.
继续坎昆。
And then you sync
然后你同步
and you wait for the fork to happen.
然后您等待叉子发生。
You verify things.
您验证事情。
And the nice thing about this
而这真是太好了
is that you can still communicate
是你仍然可以交流
to the existing nodes.
到现有节点。
So you can get transactions
这样你就可以得到交易
from the live network.
来自实时网络。
So while you are testing
因此，当您进行测试时
your new functionality,
您的新功能，
you are still getting some information,
您仍在获得一些信息，
some transactions
一些交易
from actual activity
来自实际活动
in the mainnet.
在主网中。
So a very nice way to test
这是一种非常好的测试方式
mainly with blobs.
主要带有斑点。
This was used a lot.
这被很多使用了。
And lastly, the public testnets,
最后，公共测试网，
which have been GURLY, which is now deprecated.
已经被贬低了。
We have Sipolia and Holesky.
我们有西波利和霍尔斯基。
They both serve different purposes.
他们都有不同的目的。
And yeah, mostly this is for applications to be,
是的，大多数情况下是为了使应用程序
for them to be able to test their implementations
让他们能够测试他们的实现
on the new functionality of the fork.
关于叉子的新功能。
Yeah, I'm just going to go very quickly through Ethereum security.
是的，我将通过以太坊安全迅速前进。
There's an Ethereum security group in the Ethereum Foundation.
以太坊基金会有一个以太坊安全组织。
They are very dedicated to all of these specific issues.
他们非常致力于所有这些特定问题。
Mainly, they test.
主要是他们测试。
They also perform tests, which go into, for example,
他们还执行测试，例如
the analysis of these attacks and all that stuff,
这些攻击和所有这些东西的分析，
that complex stuff that becomes a security issue.
那个复杂的东西成为安全问题。
They are the people that are best suited to respond
他们是最适合回应的人
most of the questions that you could have about security.
关于安全性的大多数问题。
But I'm gonna go over it a little bit.
但是我要仔细研究一下。
The main things that can go wrong
可能出错的主要事情
in the inclusion layer side, for example,
例如，在包含层侧
is that when a client does, like, invalidates a block
当客户确实这样做时，会使一个块无效
that fully complies with the Ethereum specification,
这完全符合以太坊规范，
This means that I have block that is correct,
这意味着我有正确的障碍，
and then my client, for some reason,
然后是我的客户，出于某种原因，
decided that it was not correct,
认为这是不正确的，
and then it just rejects it.
然后它只是拒绝它。
That means that all of the people running that client,
这意味着所有运行该客户的人，
that specific client,
那个特定的客户，
are going to go out of sync with the network
将与网络不同步
and are going into a fork.
并进入叉子。
There are a lot of variables,
有很多变量，
and many things will happen
很多事情会发生
depending on the weight of the distribution
取决于分布的重量
of how many people are running that actual client.
关于有多少人经营那个实际客户。
I'm not going to go into detail,
我不会详细介绍，
but this is one of the possible things.
但这是可能的事情之一。
Also, the other thing that happens,
另外，发生的另一件事，
so you have a valid,
所以你有有效的
this is a little bit worse, to be honest.
老实说，这有点糟糕。
This is when your client receives a backlog
这是您的客户收到积压的时候
that is invalid,
那是无效的，
and you pass it as valid.
您将其传递给有效。
This is worse because you are validating something
这更糟，因为您正在验证某些东西
that is out of specification,
这是出于规格，
that is very risky.
这很冒险。
This is something that we take special care on
这是我们特别注意的
when we are designing a test
当我们设计测试时
inside of the test repository.
在测试存储库中。
Also, another example is the denial service
另外，另一个例子是拒绝服务
during block execution.
在块执行期间。
If a client just takes a transaction or a block
如果客户只是进行交易或块
and it just takes so much time to execute,
而且执行需要很多时间，
that could be also deemed like a denial service.
这也可以被视为拒绝服务。
It's another possible security concern that we can have.
这是我们可能存在的另一个可能的安全问题。
On the consensus layer side,
在共识层侧，
something different is that depending on the faulty nodes
不同的是，取决于故障节点
that you have, for example,
例如，你有
you have less than 32% of the clients that are misbehaving
您有不到行为的客户不到32％
and then they are not following
然后他们不关注
the theorem consensus specification for any reason.
定理共识规范出于任何原因。
Less than 32% is the least concerning scenario.
少于32％的情况最少。
So you can miss slots
所以你可能会错过老虎机
and your chain will miss some at stations.
您的连锁店会错过一些车站。
You will see some hiccups, but nothing will happen.
您会看到一些打ic，但是什么都不会发生。
The chain will still finalize.
链条仍将最终确定。
So everything carries on as if nothing happened.
因此，一切都好像什么都没发生。
If you have 33 or more percent of the majority,
如果您有33％或以上的大多数百分比，
you can cause, if the client fails,
如果客户失败，您可能会导致
you can cause a delay finality.
您可能会导致延迟最终性。
So what happens is that the chain,
所以发生的是链，
if there's a split and 33% of the clients
如果有分裂和33％的客户
go through this route,
穿过这条路线，
it means that the main chain will not finalize.
这意味着主链不会最终确定。
So that's bad, but it's very recoverable.
所以这很糟糕，但是非常可恢复。
It's not as bad as other.
它不如其他人那么糟糕。
50% or more you can disrupt the fork choice
50％或以上，您可以破坏叉子选择
it means that you have 50% of the nodes
这意味着您有50％的节点
then you will disrupt how the clients behave
那么您将破坏客户的行为
and how the clients choose what chain to follow
以及客户如何选择遵循哪个链
depending on what the majority of clients is
取决于大多数客户是什么
and you have the last and the most concerning one
而且您拥有最后一个也是最令人关注的
is the 66% or more percent of the fault clients
是66％或更多的错误客户
this means that you have a superior majority of clients
这意味着您拥有较高的客户
failing because of the same thing
由于同样的事情而失败
which means that they can finalize the chain.
这意味着他们可以最终确定链条。
This is the most risky behavior that we can find
这是我们能找到的最冒险的行为
in security-related concerns.
在与安全有关的问题中。
It's very bad.
这很糟糕。
It probably will require intervention of some sort.
它可能需要某种干预。
At the moment, I don't think I am capable of explaining
目前，我认为我没有能力解释
what will happen in that scenario,
在这种情况下会发生什么
but it's one of the things that we'll always have to consider.
但这是我们始终必须考虑的事情之一。
That's why we do so much testing before any,
这就是为什么我们在任何之前进行大量测试的原因
even considering launching domain it and we have the back bounty if you guys like
即使考虑启动域名，如果你们喜欢
this you like you you guys like security you have an eye for to finding security
您喜欢你们喜欢安全的人，您需要寻找安全
concerns in software this is a place where you can shine you go into the
软件中的担忧这是您可以发光的地方
bounty bounty theorem dark and then you can get a nice bounty if you find
赏金赏金定理黑暗，然后如果您发现，您可以得到一个不错的赏金
something that can clearly and indeed can disrupt the live networks.
可以清楚并且确实可以破坏实时网络的东西。
And to get an example of all the public, previous public disclosures that have happened in the past,
为了获得所有公众的例子，过去发生的以前的公开披露，
you can go into this repository, which contains actual documented security issues that have
您可以进入此存储库，其中包含具有实际记录的安全问题
happened, that have been disclosed, sorry, in the past, but it may not because there was bounty,
碰巧的是，过去曾透露过的，但这可能不是因为有赏金
and they were privately disclosed. The main encouragement of this slide is
他们被私下披露。这张幻灯片的主要鼓励是
do not try to, if you find something that you think got disrupted, go into here you will receive bounty
不要尝试，如果您发现自己认为被干扰的东西，请进入这里，您会收到赏金
and you will not harm the network in any way. So it's like a white hat
而且您不会以任何方式损害网络。所以就像白帽
situation. And that's basically it, that's my presentation. If you have any questions
情况。基本上就是这样，这就是我的演讲。如有任何问题
These are my handles, Twitter, GitHub.
这些是我的手柄，Twitter，github。
If you guys are interested in testing, just hit me up.
如果你们有兴趣测试，那就打我。
I will answer more questions if you have them.
如果您有问题，我会回答更多问题。
Thank you so much again, Mario.
再次非常感谢，马里奥。
Amazing stuff.
很棒的东西。
Yeah, let me check if we have some closing questions,
是的，让我检查我们是否有一些结束问题，
but I think we are good, man, because we are like 15 minutes over,
但是我认为我们很好，伙计，因为我们大约15分钟了，
and you've dedicated a lot of great time to us you you gave us a look man i think people will
而且，您为我们致力了很多美好的时光
have to also see the presentation again to catch all the details there uh man uh it was intense
还必须再次查看演示文稿，以捕捉那里的所有细节，嗯，这很激烈
it was long so i really appreciate your time uh it was really great um yeah yeah thank you so much
这很长，所以我真的很感谢你的时间嗯，真的很棒，是的，是的，非常感谢
I also learned a lot. Maybe if you could point people who want to learn and start contributing
我也学到了很多。也许如果您可以指出想要学习并开始贡献的人
in some meaningful way, what would be the one place you point them to?
以某种有意义的方式，您指出的一个地方是什么？
We need help in any of the repositories that you have seen in this presentation. Whatever
我们需要在您在本演示文稿中看到的任何存储库中的帮助。任何
piques your interest the most, I think that's the best place that you can start with.
最能使您的兴趣引起您的兴趣，我认为这是您可以开始的最好的地方。
But anything is welcome.
但是，欢迎一切。
And you can start also, all the repositories have the,
您也可以开始，所有存储库都有
normally the publish issues with first good issue tag.
通常，出版问题具有第一个好问题标签。
That's the place to start in each of the repositories.
那是每个存储库中开始的地方。
I'll make sure to, because we have the execution specters
我会确保，因为我们有执行幽灵
that we maintain, I will make sure that after this,
我们坚持，我将确保此后，
we will try to think of many first good new issues
我们将尝试考虑许多第一个好的新问题
to set them in the execution specters
将它们设置在执行幽灵中
if you want to go there, or you have also,
如果您想去那里，或者您也有
So I will make sure that something new pops up.
因此，我将确保新事物弹出。
Amazing.
惊人的。
Yeah.
是的。
Yeah, thank you so much again.
是的，再次非常感谢。
It was really great to have, like, Mario Tandem here in the APSG.
像马里奥在APSG的马里奥串联一样，真是太好了。
So it was fun.
所以很有趣。
And I think, yeah, we will work it up.
而且我认为，是的，我们会努力工作。
Yeah, also, like, you are in the Discord server.
是的，也一样，您在Discord服务器中。
So if people bother you there, please excuse.
因此，如果人们在那里打扰您，请原谅。
But they might have some extra questions, I guess.
但是我想他们可能会有一些额外的问题。
Yeah, thank you so much.
是的，非常感谢。
again. And yeah, thank you so much for all the people who've been following, asking questions.
再次。是的，非常感谢您所有一直关注的人问问题。
It's been it's been an intense one. So I'll see you guys next week. Yeah.
一直是一个激烈的人。所以下周我会见大家。是的。
Ciao. Thank you.
Ciao。谢谢。
Have a great day. Thank you so much again. Bye bye.
祝你有美好的一天。再次非常感谢。再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。